<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Jeremy Rubin</title>
 <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="/"/>
 <updated>2021-09-23T18:00:30+00:00</updated>
 <id></id>
 <author>
   <name>Jeremy Rubin</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>CheckSequenceVerify DISCOURAGE_UPGRADABLE_NOPS Defect</title>
   <link href="/bitcoin/2021/09/03/upgradable-nops-flaw/"/>
   <updated>2021-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/bitcoin/2021/09/03/upgradable-nops-flaw</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The other day I was writing some tests for BIP-119 (shoutout
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/glozow&quot;&gt;Gloria&lt;/a&gt; for the detailed feedback on improving
tests). I noticed something peculiar while attempting to write static test
vectors for CTV. This peculiar thing led me to discover a minor flaw in
Bitcoin’s interpreter – it isn’t going to break anything in the short term,
but it has implications for how certain upgrades might be done in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the interpreter we pass specific flags in at different times to check
different rules at different times. This is used because we generally want the
Mempool to be “restrictive” and block validation to be unrestrictive.  That
sounds like the opposite of what you would want, but it’s because we want to
ensure that we never break a consensus rule, so our mempool is “strict” to
protect e.g. a miner from making a bad block, because our node’s understanding
of consensus validation is less strict so we always know the mempool is full of
stuff that will pass consensus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the specific types of “stricter” that is in the mempool is for things
that may be changed in the future. For example, Taproot (a change proposed to
Bitcoin) uses a Witness V1 script. Before Taproot activates, Witness V1 Scripts
are &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; valid no matter if they’re signed or not. After it activates, a
new rule takes effect in consensus, and Witness V1 Scripts will be processed in
accordance with Taproot’s rules. Because the Mempool is stricter, it never lets in
any Witness V1 script spends until it knows how to properly validate it. That way,
for a miner who doesn’t want to upgrade to Taproot, they can use the old rules in their
Mempool and not ever mine a bad block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the flags used for this purpose is DISCOURAGE_UPGRADABLE_NOPS. A NOP
is simply an opcode in bitcoin that has no effect (nada). In the future,
someone could add a rule to that NOP (e.g., check that the stack args present
when the NOP executes satisfy some properties or the transaction is invalid,
but do not remove anything from the stack so that the old consensus rules still
seem correct). This is sufficient for consensus, but maybe people have decided
that they want to create a bunch of outputs with NOPs in it because they are
cute. Then, a fork that would add new semantics to a NOP would have the impact
of locking people out of their wallets.  To prevent this, the Mempool uses the
rule DISCOURAGE_UPGRADABLE_NOPS which makes it so that if you try to
broadcast an output script with a NOP it gets bounced from the Mempool (but not
consensus of course, should a deviant miner mine such a transaction). Hopefully
our users get the message to not use NOPs because we… discourage upgradable
nops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CheckSequenceVerify (CSV) was one such NOP before it grew up to be a big n’
important opcode. Essentially all that CSV does is check that the sequence
field is set in a particular manner. This lets you set relative block and time
lock (e.g., takes this much time before a coin is spendable again). However,
it’s possible that we might come up with new kinds of lock times in the future,
so we have a bit we can set in the sequence that makes it ignored for consensus
purposes. Maybe in the future, someone would find something nice to do with it,
eh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the sequence verification code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-c++ highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;case&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;OP_CHECKSEQUENCEVERIFY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;flags&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;SCRIPT_VERIFY_CHECKSEQUENCEVERIFY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// not enabled; treat as a NOP3&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;break&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;stack&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;set_error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;serror&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;SCRIPT_ERR_INVALID_STACK_OPERATION&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// nSequence, like nLockTime, is a 32-bit unsigned integer&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// field. See the comment in CHECKLOCKTIMEVERIFY regarding&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// 5-byte numeric operands.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;CScriptNum&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;nSequence&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;stacktop&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fRequireMinimal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// In the rare event that the argument may be &amp;lt; 0 due to&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// some arithmetic being done first, you can always use&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// 0 MAX CHECKSEQUENCEVERIFY.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;nSequence&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;set_error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;serror&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;SCRIPT_ERR_NEGATIVE_LOCKTIME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// To provide for future soft-fork extensibility, if the&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// operand has the disabled lock-time flag set,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// CHECKSEQUENCEVERIFY behaves as a NOP.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;nSequence&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;CTxIn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;SEQUENCE_LOCKTIME_DISABLE_FLAG&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;break&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// Compare the specified sequence number with the input.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;checker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;CheckSequence&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;nSequence&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;set_error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;serror&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;SCRIPT_ERR_UNSATISFIED_LOCKTIME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;break&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spot anything funky? Look closer…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-c++ highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// To provide for future soft-fork extensibility, if the&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// operand has the disabled lock-time flag set,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// CHECKSEQUENCEVERIFY behaves as a NOP.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;nSequence&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;CTxIn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;SEQUENCE_LOCKTIME_DISABLE_FLAG&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;break&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, where we say it behaves as a NOP we don’t check any rules and skip the checks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See where the problem lies? If we ever &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; get around to a future upgrade
here, then old miners who refuse to upgrade would be more than happy to accept
invalid transactions into their mempool, and then following the fork, would end
up mining invalid blocks leading to potential network partitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That would be bad! Let’s not do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we really should be doing is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-c++ highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// To provide for future soft-fork extensibility, if the&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// operand has the disabled lock-time flag set,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// CHECKSEQUENCEVERIFY behaves as a NOP.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;nSequence&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;CTxIn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;SEQUENCE_LOCKTIME_DISABLE_FLAG&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;flags&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;SCRIPT_VERIFY_DISCOURAGE_UPGRADABLE_NOPS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;set_error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;serror&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;SCRIPT_ERR_DISCOURAGE_UPGRADABLE_NOPS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;break&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is exactly what I propose to do in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/22871&quot;&gt;this PR&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this solution is adopted, then after the last release of the Bitcoin Core
Implementation that has the unpatched code goes
&lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoincore.org/en/lifecycle/&quot;&gt;End-of-Life&lt;/a&gt;, we could safely deploy
new sequence rules. Because it takes a while for software to go EOL, I hope we
can patch this soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Infrastructure Bill: It's Go Time for Radical Self Custody</title>
   <link href="/bitcoin/2021/08/02/infrastructure-bill-thoughts/"/>
   <updated>2021-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/bitcoin/2021/08/02/infrastructure-bill-thoughts</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/JeremyRubin/utxos.org/pull/4&quot;&gt;TL;DR: click here to answer call to action&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/JeremyRubin/utxos.org/pull/4&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/bitcoin/virginchadcustody.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The infrastructure bill draft has been circulating which contains language that
would have massive impact for the crypto ecosystem (and Bitcoin) in the United
States, and most likely globally. The broad implication of the proposed bill is
that many types of service provider would be categorized as brokers, even if
fully ‘non custodial’. E.g., a coinjoin coordinator might be a broker, even if
they never take control of the funds, because they are facilitating a
transaction. There’s a lot of nuance, and the language is still being changed,
so we’ll see where it lands. But that’s not the point of this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of this blog post is that we need to &lt;em&gt;hurry the fuck up&lt;/em&gt; and improve
the self-sovereign software available and widely used by bitcoiners. You heard
me right, &lt;em&gt;hurry the fuck up&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there’s space for debate around perfect designs and optima for protocol
improvements, these discussions take years to turn into code running in end
users wallets. I do not believe that we have time to leisurely improve
self-sovereign custody solutions while regulators figure out a wrench to throw
in our spokes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why am I so concerned about this bill in particular? A confidential source
tells me that this language came out of the blue, an executive branch driven
regulatory ninja attack of sorts. Normally, when the government looks to
regulate an industry, the provisions and terms get floated around by
legislators for a long while with industry input, comment periods, and more.
Then, when a bill or other rules get passed, it’s something that the industry
has at least had a chance to weigh in on and prepare for. My source claims no
one has seen the clauses in the infrastructure bill before, and they infer that
may mean this is a part of a broader crack-down coming from specific political
personalities and agencies. This means we may be seeing government actions
further restricting users’ rights in the pipeline much sooner than anyone could
anticipate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve long been saying that we should be deploying &lt;a href=&quot;https://utxos.org&quot;&gt;BIP-119
CTV&lt;/a&gt; for congestion control &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; we see broad congestion
on the network. If you wait until a problem is manifest, it can take years to
deploy a solution. This merits proactivity in solving a problem before it
comes. Today, the need to improve self-custody looms urgently on the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CTV is not a panacea solution. It doesn’t magically fix all custodial issues.
But, along with &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.sapio-lang.org&quot;&gt;Sapio&lt;/a&gt;, it does offer a pathway
to dramatically improving self custody options, letting users customize vault
smart contracts which do not depend on any third parties. Deploying CTV now is
an opportunity to put in motion the wheels for broad ecosystem support for
these enhanced custody protocols. We may come up with better options in the
future which may obsolete CTV in place of more clever technologies. I cheer
those efforts. But we need solutions for Tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A soft fork activation for CTV could be deployable for Bitcoin imminently,
should the community embrace it. The spec is nearly 2 years old, the code has
required only small updates to be mergeable with other changes to Bitcoin Core.
The review burden is 185 lines of consensus code, and a couple hundred lines of
tests. To that end I believe it is prudent for the Bitcoin community to embrace
the deployment of CTV and I’m calling on the community to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/JeremyRubin/utxos.org/pull/4&quot;&gt;soft-signal
intent&lt;/a&gt; for a soft-fork
activation of CTV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We cannot control what rules state authorities attempt to mandate. But we can
individually control our own compliance with measures we see as unjust, and as
a community we can advance technologies and solutions that ensure that choice
remains squarely in the hands of every user and not the service providers they
may use.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>BIP-118 What Gets Hashed Chart</title>
   <link href="/bitcoin/2021/07/09/bip-118-sighash-chart/"/>
   <updated>2021-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/bitcoin/2021/07/09/bip-118-sighash-chart</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As a part of my ongoing review of BIP-118 I put together a
&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1KeWJ_cly9zoRX5_h70RTniRT2m8_iaVceK_aF6obWeM&quot;&gt;chart&lt;/a&gt;
of what gets hashed under the current proposal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1KeWJ_cly9zoRX5_h70RTniRT2m8_iaVceK_aF6obWeM&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/bip-118.png&quot; alt=&quot;BIP-118 Chart&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not tightly checked to be free of errors, but I figured such a chart would be
helpful for folks evaluating BIP-118.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the BIPs (generally, incl 34x) could be updated to present the
information in such a chart – at least for me it’s much clearer than following
a bunch of conditional logic (maybe if there’s ever desire for some consensus
refactoring this could be a table in the code replacing the cond logic).
A few highlighted nuances:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;input index is never signed (i previously thought one mode signed it). Key reuse under &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;APOAS | Default&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;APOAS | All&lt;/code&gt; is a bit extra unsafe given susceptibility to the “half-spend” problem. This limits usability of APO for covenants a-la CTV because you can’t stop someone from adding inputs to your contract nor can you prevent half-spend problems when reusing addresses.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;APO signs the Amounts, APOAS never does.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;APO signs both the SPK and the Tapleaf hash, meaning that APO binds itself to the entire script rather than just it’s fragment. There’s no setting which is “just this fragment”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;APO’s signature binds it to a specific script fragment &lt;em&gt;within&lt;/em&gt; a taproot key, but not a specific script path&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the flag “default” is not really a flag at all – when default is used (as a or’d byte) there are different results than when default is inferred (by absence of a byte) (this is maybe a bitcoin core specific quirk).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are 16 different possible modes total, so all combinations of flags mean &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; (advisable or not as with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ACP | None&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;*| Default&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;*| All&lt;/code&gt; overlap, so there’s an opportunity to either reserve or assign 4 additional sighash modes if desired. These could cover some of the gaps above, or be saved for future purposes rather than be wasted now. Another point of interest is – not to rock the boat – but because BIP-118 is defining a new key type we could do away with the notion that sighash flags are “flags” and convert to an enum (e.g., numbered 0-256 for whatever combination of fields each would incur) and give each signature type a sensible name, rather than thinking of things as a combo of flags (e.g., &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;APOAS&lt;/code&gt; is not some intersection of what &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;APO&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ACP&lt;/code&gt; do independently).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Quantum Proofing Bitcoin with a CAT</title>
   <link href="/blog/2021/07/06/quantum-bitcoin/"/>
   <updated>2021-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/blog/2021/07/06/quantum-bitcoin</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently published &lt;a href=&quot;https://rubin.io/blog/2021/07/02/signing-5-bytes/&quot;&gt;a blog
post&lt;/a&gt; about signing up to a
5 byte value using Bitcoin script arithmetic and Lamport signatures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By itself, this is neat, but a little limited. What if we could sign longer
messages? If we can sign up to 20 bytes, we could sign a HASH160 digest which
is most likely quantum safe…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would it mean if we signed the HASH160 digest of a signature? What the
what? Why would we do that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, as it turns out, even if a quantum computer were able to crack ECDSA, it
would yield revealing the private key but not the ability to malleate the
content of what was actually signed.  I asked my good friend and cryptographer
&lt;a href=&quot;https://madars.org/&quot;&gt;Madars Virza&lt;/a&gt; if my intuition was correct, and he
confirmed that it should be sufficient, but it’s definitely worth closer
analysis before relying on this. While the ECDSA signature can be malleated to a
different, negative form, if the signature is otherwise made immalleable there
should only be one value the commitment can be opened to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we required the ECDSA signature be signed with a quantum proof signature
algorithm, then we’d have a quantum proof Bitcoin! And the 5 byte signing scheme
we discussed previously is a Lamport signature, which is quantum secure.
Unfortunately, we need at least 20 contiguous bytes… so we need some sort of
OP_CAT like operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OP_CAT can’t be directly soft forked to Segwit v0 because it modifies the
stack, so instead we’ll (for simplicity) also show how to use a new opcode that
uses verify semantics, OP_SUBSTRINGEQUALVERIFY that checks a splice of a string
for equality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Fun Fact: OP_CAT existed in Bitcoin untill 2010, when Satoshi “secretly”
forked out a bunch of opcodes. So in theory the original Bitcoin implementation
supported Post Quantum cryptography out of the box!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;... FOR j in 0..=5
    &amp;lt;0&amp;gt;
    ... FOR i in 0..=31
        SWAP hash160 DUP &amp;lt;H(K_j_i_1)&amp;gt; EQUAL IF DROP &amp;lt;2**i&amp;gt; ADD ELSE &amp;lt;H(K_j_i_0)&amp;gt; EQUALVERIFY ENDIF
    ... END FOR
    TOALTSTACK
... END FOR

DUP HASH160

... IF CAT AVAILABLE
    FROMALTSTACK
    ... FOR j in 0..=5
        FROMALTSTACK
        CAT
    ... END FOR
    EQUALVERIFY
... ELSE SUBSTRINGEQUALVERIFY AVAILABLE
    ... FOR j in 0..=5
        FROMALTSTACK &amp;lt;0+j*4&amp;gt; &amp;lt;4+j*4&amp;gt; SUBSTRINGEQUALVERIFY DROP DROP DROP
    ...  END FOR
    DROP
... END IF

&amp;lt;pk&amp;gt; CHECKSIG
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a long script… but will it fit? We need to verify 20 bytes of message
each bit takes around 10 bytes script, an average of 3.375 bytes per number
(counting pushes), and two 21 bytes keys = 55.375 bytes of program space and 21
bytes of witness element per bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It fits! &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;20*8*55.375 = 8860&lt;/code&gt;, which leaves 1140 bytes less than the limit for
the rest of the logic, which is plenty (around 15-40 bytes required for the rest
of the logic, leaving 1100 free for custom signature checking). The stack size
is 160 elements for the hash gadget, 3360 bytes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can probably be made a bit more efficient by expanding to a ternary
representation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;        SWAP hash160 DUP &amp;lt;H(K_j_i_0)&amp;gt; EQUAL  IF DROP  ELSE &amp;lt;3**i&amp;gt; SWAP DUP &amp;lt;H(K_j_i_T)&amp;gt; EQUAL IF DROP SUB ELSE &amp;lt;H(K_j_i_1)&amp;gt; EQUALVERIFY ADD  ENDIF ENDIF
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This should bring it up to roughly 85 bytes per trit, and there should be 101
trits (&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;log(2**160)/log(3) == 100.94&lt;/code&gt;), so about 8560 bytes… a bit cheaper!
But the witness stack is “only” &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;2121&lt;/code&gt; bytes…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a homework exercise, maybe someone can prove the optimal choice of radix for
this protocol… My guess is that base 4 is optimal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;taproot&quot;&gt;Taproot?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about Taproot? As far as I’m aware the commitment scheme (&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Q = pG + hash(pG
|| m)G&lt;/code&gt;) can be securely opened to m even with a quantum computer (finding &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;q&lt;/code&gt;
such that &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;qG = Q&lt;/code&gt; might be trivial, but suppose key path was disabled, then
finding m and p such that the taproot equation holds should be difficult because
of the hash, but I’d need to certify that claim better).  Therefore this
script can nest inside of a Tapscript path – Tapscript also does not impose a
length limit, 32 byte hashes could be used as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, to make keys reusable, there could be many Lamport keys comitted inside
a taproot tree so that an address could be used for thousands of times before
expiring. This could be used as a measure to protect accidental use rather than
to support it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, Schnorr actually has a stronger non-malleability property than ECDSA,
the signatures will be binding to the approved transaction and once Lamport
signed, even a quantum computer could not steal the funds.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>CheckSigFromStack for 5 Byte Values</title>
   <link href="/blog/2021/07/02/signing-5-bytes/"/>
   <updated>2021-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/blog/2021/07/02/signing-5-bytes</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently published &lt;a href=&quot;https://rubin.io/blog/2021/07/02/covenants/&quot;&gt;a blog post&lt;/a&gt;
about covenants on Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Readers were quick to point out I hadn’t
fully explained myself on a claim I made that you can do a form of
CheckSigFromStack in Bitcoin today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I thought it would be worthwhile to fully describe the technique – for the
archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two insights in this post:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;to use a bitwise expansion of the number&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;to use a lamport signature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at the code in python and then translate to bitcoin script:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;add_bit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;idx&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;preimage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;image_0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;image_1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;s&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sha256&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;preimage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;s&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;image_1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;idx&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;s&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;image_0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;assert&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;False&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;get_signed_number&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;witnesses&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;List&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Hash&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;keys&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;List&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Tuple&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Hash&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Hash&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]]):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;acc&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;idx&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;preimage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;enumerate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;witnesses&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;acc&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;add_bit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;idx&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;preimage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;keys&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;idx&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;][&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;keys&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;idx&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;][&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;])&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what’s going on here? The signer generates a key which is a list of pairs of
hash images to create the script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To sign, the signer provides a witness of a list of preimages that match one or the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During validation, the network adds up a weighted value per preimage and checks
that there are no left out values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s imagine a concrete use case: I want a third party to post-hoc sign a sequence lock. This is 16 bits.
I can form the following script:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;pk&amp;gt; checksigverify
0
SWAP sha256 DUP &amp;lt;H(K_0_1)&amp;gt; EQUAL IF DROP &amp;lt;1&amp;gt; ADD ELSE &amp;lt;H(K_0_0)&amp;gt; EQUALVERIFY ENDIF
SWAP sha256 DUP &amp;lt;H(K_1_1)&amp;gt; EQUAL IF DROP &amp;lt;1&amp;lt;&amp;lt;1&amp;gt; ADD ELSE &amp;lt;H(K_1_0)&amp;gt; EQUALVERIFY ENDIF
SWAP sha256 DUP &amp;lt;H(K_2_1)&amp;gt; EQUAL IF DROP &amp;lt;1&amp;lt;&amp;lt;2&amp;gt; ADD ELSE &amp;lt;H(K_2_0)&amp;gt; EQUALVERIFY ENDIF
SWAP sha256 DUP &amp;lt;H(K_3_1)&amp;gt; EQUAL IF DROP &amp;lt;1&amp;lt;&amp;lt;3&amp;gt; ADD ELSE &amp;lt;H(K_3_0)&amp;gt; EQUALVERIFY ENDIF
SWAP sha256 DUP &amp;lt;H(K_4_1)&amp;gt; EQUAL IF DROP &amp;lt;1&amp;lt;&amp;lt;4&amp;gt; ADD ELSE &amp;lt;H(K_4_0)&amp;gt; EQUALVERIFY ENDIF
SWAP sha256 DUP &amp;lt;H(K_5_1)&amp;gt; EQUAL IF DROP &amp;lt;1&amp;lt;&amp;lt;5&amp;gt; ADD ELSE &amp;lt;H(K_5_0)&amp;gt; EQUALVERIFY ENDIF
SWAP sha256 DUP &amp;lt;H(K_6_1)&amp;gt; EQUAL IF DROP &amp;lt;1&amp;lt;&amp;lt;6&amp;gt; ADD ELSE &amp;lt;H(K_6_0)&amp;gt; EQUALVERIFY ENDIF
SWAP sha256 DUP &amp;lt;H(K_7_1)&amp;gt; EQUAL IF DROP &amp;lt;1&amp;lt;&amp;lt;7&amp;gt; ADD ELSE &amp;lt;H(K_7_0)&amp;gt; EQUALVERIFY ENDIF
SWAP sha256 DUP &amp;lt;H(K_8_1)&amp;gt; EQUAL IF DROP &amp;lt;1&amp;lt;&amp;lt;8&amp;gt; ADD ELSE &amp;lt;H(K_8_0)&amp;gt; EQUALVERIFY ENDIF
SWAP sha256 DUP &amp;lt;H(K_9_1)&amp;gt; EQUAL IF DROP &amp;lt;1&amp;lt;&amp;lt;9&amp;gt; ADD ELSE &amp;lt;H(K_9_0)&amp;gt; EQUALVERIFY ENDIF
SWAP sha256 DUP &amp;lt;H(K_10_1)&amp;gt; EQUAL IF DROP &amp;lt;1&amp;lt;&amp;lt;10&amp;gt; ADD ELSE &amp;lt;H(K_10_0)&amp;gt; EQUALVERIFY ENDIF
SWAP sha256 DUP &amp;lt;H(K_11_1)&amp;gt; EQUAL IF DROP &amp;lt;1&amp;lt;&amp;lt;11&amp;gt; ADD ELSE &amp;lt;H(K_11_0)&amp;gt; EQUALVERIFY ENDIF
SWAP sha256 DUP &amp;lt;H(K_12_1)&amp;gt; EQUAL IF DROP &amp;lt;1&amp;lt;&amp;lt;12&amp;gt; ADD ELSE &amp;lt;H(K_12_0)&amp;gt; EQUALVERIFY ENDIF
SWAP sha256 DUP &amp;lt;H(K_13_1)&amp;gt; EQUAL IF DROP &amp;lt;1&amp;lt;&amp;lt;13&amp;gt; ADD ELSE &amp;lt;H(K_13_0)&amp;gt; EQUALVERIFY ENDIF
SWAP sha256 DUP &amp;lt;H(K_14_1)&amp;gt; EQUAL IF DROP &amp;lt;1&amp;lt;&amp;lt;14&amp;gt; ADD ELSE &amp;lt;H(K_14_0)&amp;gt; EQUALVERIFY ENDIF
SWAP sha256 DUP &amp;lt;H(K_15_1)&amp;gt; EQUAL IF DROP &amp;lt;1&amp;lt;&amp;lt;15&amp;gt; ADD ELSE &amp;lt;H(K_15_0)&amp;gt; EQUALVERIFY ENDIF
CHECKSEQUENCEVERIFY
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to sign a 16 bit value V, the owner of K simply puts on the stack the
binary representation of V indexed into the K. E.g., to sign &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;53593&lt;/code&gt;, first
expand to binary &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;0b1101000101011001&lt;/code&gt;, then put the appropriate K values on the
stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;K_15_1
K_14_1
K_13_0
K_12_1
K_11_0
K_10_0
K_9_0
K_8_1
K_7_0
K_6_1
K_5_0
K_4_1
K_3_1
K_2_0
K_1_0
K_0_1
&amp;lt;sig&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This technique is kind of bulky! It’s around 80x16 = 1280 length for the
gadget, and 528 bytes for the witnesses. So it is &lt;em&gt;doable&lt;/em&gt;, if not a bit
expensive. There might be some more efficient scripts for this – would a
trinary representation be more efficient?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The values that can be signed can be range limited either post-hoc (using
OP_WITHIN) or internally as was done with the 16 bit value circuit where it’s
impossible to do more than 16 bits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keys &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; be reused across scripts, but signatures may only be constructed one
time because a third party could take two signed messages and construct an
unintended value (e.g., if you sign both 4 and 2 then a third party could
construct 6).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are certain applications where this could be used for an effect – for
example, an oracle might have a bonding contract whereby posessing any K_i_0
and K_i_1 allows the burning of funds.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Templates, Eltoo, and Covenants, Oh My!</title>
   <link href="/blog/2021/07/02/covenants/"/>
   <updated>2021-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/blog/2021/07/02/covenants</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/post-covenant-meme.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been following The Discourse, you probably know that Taproot is
merged, locked in, and will activate later this November. What you might not
know is what’s coming next… and you wouldn’t be alone in that. There are a
number of fantastic proposals floating around to further improve Bitcoin, but
there’s no clear picture on what is ready to be added next and on what
timeline. No one – core developer, technically enlightened individuals, power
users, or plebs – can claim to know otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post I’m going to describe 4 loosely related possible upgrades to
Bitcoin – SH_APO (BIP-118), OP_CAT, OP_CSFS, and OP_CTV (BIP-119). These four
upgrades all relate to how the next generation of stateful smart contracts can
be built on top of bitcoin. As such, there’s natural overlap – and competition
– for mindshare for review and deployment. This post is my attempt to stitch
together a path we might take to roll them out and why that ordering makes
sense. This post is for developers and engineers building in the Bitcoin space,
but is intended to be followable by anyone technical or not who has a keen
interest in Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bitcoin-eschews-roadmaps-and-agendas&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Eschews Roadmaps and Agendas.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I provide this maxim to make clear that this document is by no means an
official roadmap, narrative, or prioritization. However, it is my own
assessment of what the current most pragmatic approach to upgrading Bitcoin is,
based on my understanding of the state of outstanding proposals and their
interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My priorities in producing this are to open a discussion on potential new
features, risk minimization, and pragmatic design for Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;upgrade-summaries&quot;&gt;Upgrade Summaries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below follows summaries of what each upgrade would enable and how it works. You
might be tempted to skip it if you’re already familiar with the upgrades, but I
recommend reading in any case as there are a few non obvious insights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;apo-sighash_anyprevout-sighash_anyprevoutanyscript&quot;&gt;APO: SIGHASH_ANYPREVOUT, SIGHASH_ANYPREVOUTANYSCRIPT&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently proposed as
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/d616d5492bc6e6566af1b9f9e43b660bcd48ca29/bip-0118.mediawiki&quot;&gt;BIP-118&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;APO provides two new signature digest algorithms that do not commit to the coin
being spent, or the current script additionally. Essentially allowing scripts
to use outputs that didn’t exist at the time the script was made. This would be
a new promise enforced by Bitcoin (ex. “You can close this Lightning channel
and receive these coins if you give me the right proof. If a newer proof comes
in later I’ll trust that one instead.”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;APO’s primary purpose is to enable off chain protocols like
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blockstream.com/2018/04/30/en-eltoo-next-lightning/&quot;&gt;Eltoo&lt;/a&gt;, an
improved non-punitive payment channel protocol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;APO can also
&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2019-June/017038.html&quot;&gt;emulate&lt;/a&gt;
some of the main features of CTV and could be made to work with Sapio,
partially. See the complimentary upgrades section for more detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;cat--variants&quot;&gt;CAT (+ variants)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently no BIP. However, CAT exists in
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ElementsProject/elements/blob/bd2e2d5c64d38286b2ca0519f1215bed228e4dcf/src/script/interpreter.cpp#L914-L933&quot;&gt;Elements&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoincashorg/bitcoincash.org/blob/3e2e6da8c38dab7ba12149d327bc4b259aaad684/spec/may-2018-reenabled-opcodes.md&quot;&gt;Bitcoin
Cash&lt;/a&gt;
as a 520 byte limited form, so a proposal for Bitcoin can crib heavily from
either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cat enables appending data onto other pieces of data. Diabolically simple
functionality that has many advanced use cases by itself and in concert with
other opcodes. There are many “straightforward” use cases of cat like requiring
sighash types, requiring specific R values, etc, but there are too many devious
use cases to list here.  Andrew Poelstra has a decent blogpost series (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wpsoftware.net/andrew/blog/cat-and-schnorr-tricks-i.html&quot;&gt;part
1&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wpsoftware.net/andrew/blog/cat-and-schnorr-tricks-ii.html&quot;&gt;part
ii&lt;/a&gt;) if
you’re interested to read more. In particular, with much cleverness, it seems
possible one could implement full covenants with just CAT, which covers
(inefficiently) most of the other techniques discussed in this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;csfs-checksigfromstack&quot;&gt;CSFS: CHECKSIGFROMSTACK&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently no BIP. However, CSFS exists in
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ElementsProject/elements/blob/bd2e2d5c64d38286b2ca0519f1215bed228e4dcf/src/script/interpreter.cpp#L1580-L1618&quot;&gt;Elements&lt;/a&gt;
and in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoincashorg/bitcoincash.org/blob/master/spec/op_checkdatasig.md&quot;&gt;Bitcoin
Cash&lt;/a&gt;,
so a proposal for Bitcoin can crib heavily from either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CSFS enables checking of a signature against a message and key from the stack
without including any transaction data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use cases include oracle protocols, key delegations, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://stanford2017.scalingbitcoin.org/files/Day1/SB2017_script_2_0.pdf&quot;&gt;channel update
invalidation
variant&lt;/a&gt;
(Laolu claims this can be tweaked to be fully non punitive like eltoo, but
you’ll need to bug him to write it up), and (+CAT) full covenants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ctv-op_checktemplateverify&quot;&gt;CTV: OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently proposed as
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/master/bip-0119.mediawiki&quot;&gt;BIP-119&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CTV enables committing to a specific “next” transaction from script. This is
the ability to make an unbreakable promise on chain which Bitcoin can enforce
(e.g. “This coin can only be spent to my multisig, or my backup after a
timelock”). This is a departure from normal script which is traditionally only
concerned with restrictions on the sender, CTV imposes restrictions on the
recipient. More technically, CTV is essentially the ability to embed a
signature of a specific transaction inside of a script without needing any
elliptic curve operations. The validation costs are low. For more advanced
logic, you can nest multiple different CTV Hashes either using taproot or up to
the script length limits in regular script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CTV can be used for vaults, channels, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://utxos.org/uses/&quot;&gt;many other
uses&lt;/a&gt;. There’s also
&lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.sapio-lang.org&quot;&gt;Sapio&lt;/a&gt; which is a language and toolkit for
creating many kinds of programs with CTV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CTV compliments CSFS to be able to emulate APO-like functionality
sufficient to build Eltoo, potentially making APO feature-wise redundant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;comparative-analysis&quot;&gt;Comparative Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve got the basics covered, let’s explore these upgrades
comparatively across several dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;design-specificity&quot;&gt;Design Specificity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Design Specificity” is a subjective measure of how substantially an upgrade
could change from its current design while still meeting the features goals. It
is not to be confused with security or safety. Ranked in order from most to
least design specific, with non-exhaustive lists of design questions based on
ongoing community discourse as well as my own personal understanding of what
might be desirable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CSFS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CTV&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CAT&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;APO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;explanations--open-questions&quot;&gt;Explanations &amp;amp; Open Questions:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CSFS is very simple and there is essentially a single way to implement it. Three open questions are:
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Should CSFS require some sort of tagged hash? Very likely answer is no –
tags interfere with certain use cases)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Should CSFS split the signature’s R &amp;amp; S value stack items for some
applications that otherwise may require OP_CAT? E.g. using a pinned R
 value allows you to extract a private key if ever double signed, using 2 R
 values allows pay-to-reveal-key contracts. Most likely answer is no, if that is
 desired then OP_CAT can be introduced&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Should CSFS support a cheap way to reference the taproot internal or
external key? Perhaps, can be handled with undefined upgradeable
 keytypes. One might want to use the internal key, if the signed data should be
 valid independent of the tapscript tree.  One might want to use the external
 key, if the data should only be valid for a single tapscript key + tree.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CTV is a commitment to all data that can malleate TXID besides the inputs
being spent, therefore CTV does not have much space for variation on design.
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Should the digest be reordered or formatted differently? If there were
more data on what types of covenants might be built in the future, a
 better order could be picked. Some thought has already gone into an order and
 commitments that make covenants easier, see the BIP for more. It’s also
 possible the serialization format for the variable length fields (scriptsigs,
 outputs) could be changed to make it easier to work with from script. (Maybe,
 minor change)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Should CTV include more template types? Possibly, CTV includes an upgrade
mechanism baked in for new template types, so it is extensible for future
 purposes.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Should CTV commit to the amounts? CTV does not commit to the amount that
a coin has. Input-inspecting functionality should be handled by separate
 opcodes, as CTV would be overly restrictive otherwise. E.g. dynamic fees
 through new inputs would be harder: given CTV’s design it is not possible to
 detect which field did not match therefore it is not possible to script against
 unexpected amount sent errors without some compromise (e.g. timeouts).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CAT is simplistic, and there are really few ways to implement it. However,
because it requires some restrictions for security, there are difficult to
 answer open design questions:
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What is the appropriate maximum stack size CAT should permit? Currently
the design in Elements is 520 bytes, the max general stack size permitted
 in script.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Should CAT be introduced or
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ElementsProject/elements/pull/817&quot;&gt;SHASTREAM&lt;/a&gt;,
 SUBSTRING, or another variant? There is a strong argument for SHASTREAM because
 when constructing covenants (e.g. for use with CTV) based on TX data it’s
 possible for size of a data field (e.g., serialization of all outputs) to
 exceed 520 bytes.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are many tough questions that the community has grappled with during
APO’s design and engineering process, generally asking how APO-like
 techniques can be made ‘Generally Safe’ given iit breaks current assumptions
 around address reuse.
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Should APO require chaperone signatures (in order to ensure that replay
is not done by 3rd parties)? Current Answer: No, anyone is free to burn
 their keys by revealing them to similar effect.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Should APO use key tagging to mark keys that can use APO: Current Answer:
yes, APO should be “double opt-in” (both requiring a tag and a signer to
 produce such a signature)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Should APO allow signing with the external taproot key: Current Answer:
no, because it makes APO not “double opt-in”.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Should APO optimize signing with the internal taproot key? Answer:
default key 0x01 refers to taproot internal key, so it can be made
 cheaper if you’re going to need it without having to repeat the entire key.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Should APO commit to the signing script? Answer: let’s do two variants.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Should APO instead be a larger refactoring of sighash logic that
encapsulates APO (e.g. sighash bitmasks)? Current Answer: No, APO is good
 enough to ship as is and doesn’t preclude future work.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;safety&quot;&gt;Safety&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This category covers how “safe” each change is ranked from safest to least
safe. What makes a change more or less safe is how limited and foreseeable the
uses are of a specific opcode, in other words, how well we understand what it
can do or where it might interact poorly with deployed infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CTV&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CSFS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;APO&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CAT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CTV is the safest new feature since fundamentally what it introduces is very
similar to what can be done with pre-signed transactions, so it is only a pivot
on trust and interactivity. Where there is some risk from CTV is that addresses
(or rather, invoices) that are reused might have the same program behind them
which could cause unintended behavior. This differs from the reuse problem in
APO because the problem is stateless, that is, if you verify what is behind an
address you will know what exists and does not exist. E.g., two payment channel
addresses will create distinct payment channels that updates cannot be replayed
across. In contrast with APO, paying one APO using address twice creates two
instances of the same channel, state updates from one channel can be used on
the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CSFS is the next safest, it is just a small piece of authenticated data. CSFS
and CTV are relatively close in terms of safety, but CSFS is slightly less safe
given a remote possibility of surprising  uses of it to perform unforeseen
elliptic curve operations. This functionality already exists for up to 5-byte
messages. A hash preimage revelation can emulate a signer compactly. Using
binary expansions and addition could be used to allow signing of values more
compactly (e.g., 2x16x32 byte hashes could be used to construct a signature of
a post-hoc selected Sequence lock). &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2021/07/02/signing-5-bytes/&quot;&gt;Read more here&lt;/a&gt;. Therefore it is appropriate to think of
CSFS as an expansion of the efficiency of this technique, reusability of keys,
and the types of data that can be signed over. Although CSFS is famously used
to build covenants by comparing a CSFS signature to a CHECKSIG signature and
getting transaction data onto the stack, CSFS cannot do that without CAT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;APO. This is the next safest because APO has some questions around key reuse
safety and statefulness of information. See the above description in CTV for
why this is tangibly worse for APO than CTV. &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/lightning-dev/2019-September/002176.html&quot;&gt;See more discussion of APO’s
safety &amp;amp; design trade offs
here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CAT is the least ‘safe’ in terms of extant Bitcoin concepts as it is highly
likely CAT introduces at least advanced covenants if added, especially in
conjunction with the above opcodes, but may also enable other unintended
functionality. CAT is a source of continual surprise with regards to what it
enables in composition with existing opcodes, therefore a systematic review of
composability and known uses should be done before considering it. That CAT was
forked out by Satoshi is of limited relevance as the variant proposed for
reintroduction would not have the vulnerability present initially.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;complimentary-upgrades&quot;&gt;Complimentary Upgrades&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pairings of upgrades can work together to deliver functionality that neither
could alone:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CAT + CSFS: full blown arbitrary covenants
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;With arbitrary covenants you can deploy many different kinds of smart
contracts which are out of scope for this article.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CAT + CTV: Expanded covenants
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;slightly simpler to use interface but fewer features than CSFS + CAT which can
covenant over witness data and inputs.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CTV + CSFS: Eltoo
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This can add very similar functionality to eltoo with the script fragment:
 &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CTV &amp;lt;musig(pka, pkb)&amp;gt; CSFS &amp;lt;S+1&amp;gt; CLTV&lt;/code&gt;
 The protocol is essentially identical to the Eltoo paper, however there are
 a couple subtle differences required for dynamic fee rates.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CTV + APO: Slightly Different
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Several sources have claimed that APO offers a strict superset
of CTV’s functionality (but not efficiency). This is false. Their digests
are slightly different, as such there are some niche smart contracts that could
use the differences in commitment structure for interesting effects (CTV
commits to all scriptsigs and sequences, APO cannot cover that data but can
cover a few variants of less data covered).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By all means not an exhaustive list – feel free to message me with additions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;recommendation&quot;&gt;Recommendation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My recommendation is to deliver the upgrades described in this document in the
following order:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CTV&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CSFS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;APO&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CAT/SHASTREAM/SUBSTRING/etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This recommendation comes as a synthesis of the thoughts above on the
composability, safety, and open design considerations of the various proposals
currently in flight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With CTV in place, we can begin experimenting with a wide variety of contracts
using the Sapio toolchain, as well as improve and invest in maturing the
toolchain. Mature toolchains will make it easier to safely engineer and deploy
applications making use of CTV and future upgrades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CSFS is an independent change that can be deployed/developed in parallel to or
before CTV, the implementation from Elements could be easily ported to Bitcoin.
With CSFS and CTV, Eltoo-like constructions will be possible as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;APO can then be deployed as an optimization to existing use patterns driven by
market adoption of CTV+CSFS based use. This also gives us time to kick the can
down the road on the design questions that APO prompts around generalization of
signature digests and key reuse safety.  A similar approach was &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2019-May/016996.html&quot;&gt;discussed on
the mailing
list&lt;/a&gt;,
but without the insight that CSFS + CTV was sufficient for Eltoo like
constructions, requiring CAT instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, OP_CAT can be delivered as part of an effort towards generalized
arbitrary covenants and perhaps in conjunction with some special purpose
opcodes (such as OP_CHECKINPUT) that can more easily handle common cases. CAT,
although it has safe implementations used in Elements, deserves very strict
scrutiny given it’s documented surprising uses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach represents a gradual relaxation of Bitcoin’s restrictions around
smart contract programming that introduces useful, safe primitives and gives
the community time to build and deploy useful infrastructure. The path
described in this post is an opportunity to upgrade bitcoin with simple
primitives that compose nicely for permissionless innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to those who reviewed drafts of this post and provided valuable
feedback improving the clarity and accuracy of this post, including
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pyskell&quot;&gt;pyskell&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ProofOfKeags&quot;&gt;Keagan
McClelland&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RyanTheGentry&quot;&gt;Ryan
Gentry&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/roasbeef&quot;&gt;Olaoluwa
Osuntokun&lt;/a&gt;. Edit + Feedback ≠ Endorsement.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Designing Bitcoin Contracts with Sapio</title>
   <link href="/talks/2021/06/10/bitcoin21-talk/"/>
   <updated>2021-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/talks/2021/06/10/bitcoin21-talk</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/w3FL0kEO_R4&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Bitcoin is DeFi Panel</title>
   <link href="/talks/2021/06/09/bitcoin21-panel/"/>
   <updated>2021-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/talks/2021/06/09/bitcoin21-panel</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VQgklSuo0KU&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How Taproot Could Improve Bitcoin — If It Gets Adopted</title>
   <link href="/talks/2021/06/04/unconfirmed-taproot/"/>
   <updated>2021-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/talks/2021/06/04/unconfirmed-taproot</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pAcCNDiJX-I&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fireside Chat Jeremy Rubin BTC Core Dev & Judica</title>
   <link href="/talks/2020/09/15/cryptofinally/"/>
   <updated>2020-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/talks/2020/09/15/cryptofinally</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/srMXBHkoxEM&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>BITCOIN DEVELOPER IN FOCUS</title>
   <link href="/talks/2020/09/09/vallis/"/>
   <updated>2020-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/talks/2020/09/09/vallis</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/q3pgcVfR-KY&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Sapio Stateful Smart Contracts for Bitcoin with OP_CTV</title>
   <link href="/talks/2020/07/11/reckless/"/>
   <updated>2020-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/talks/2020/07/11/reckless</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4vDuttlImPc&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>CTV Interview by Aaron van Wirdum</title>
   <link href="/talks/2020/06/22/btcmag-ctv-interview/"/>
   <updated>2020-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/talks/2020/06/22/btcmag-ctv-interview</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0rMQ1p6q36g&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>BIP-119</title>
   <link href="/talks/2020/04/06/mit-expo-2020/"/>
   <updated>2020-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/talks/2020/04/06/mit-expo-2020</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UgIEJeJg_ik&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY</title>
   <link href="/talks/2020/01/30/chaincode-3/"/>
   <updated>2020-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/talks/2020/01/30/chaincode-3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://anchor.fm/chaincode/embed/episodes/Jeremy-Rubin-and-CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY---Episode-3-eahnt3/a-a1cotkp&quot; height=&quot;102px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Bitcoin Game 66 Jeremy Rubin</title>
   <link href="/talks/2019/07/02/the-bitcoin-game/"/>
   <updated>2019-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/talks/2019/07/02/the-bitcoin-game</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FZck9V2fWn0&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Protocol Improvement Outlooks w/ Matt Corallo, Jeremy Rubin, 'Roasbeef' & Steve Lee</title>
   <link href="/talks/2019/06/29/bitcoin-2019/"/>
   <updated>2019-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/talks/2019/06/29/bitcoin-2019</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JhokT9Fg4FA&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Spork Probabilistic Bitcoin Soft Forks</title>
   <link href="/talks/2019/02/06/sbc-spork/"/>
   <updated>2019-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/talks/2019/02/06/sbc-spork</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/J1CP7qbnpqA&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Problem with ASICBOOST</title>
   <link href="/talks/2018/11/04/asicboost/"/>
   <updated>2018-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/talks/2018/11/04/asicboost</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ET2QDRZVUwc&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A hardCORE workout w/ Bitcoin Core Dev Jeremy Rubin</title>
   <link href="/talks/2018/04/23/hardcore-workout/"/>
   <updated>2018-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/talks/2018/04/23/hardcore-workout</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PKzJktErUdk&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Bitcoin Hunter</title>
   <link href="/talks/2018/01/25/reply-all/"/>
   <updated>2018-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/talks/2018/01/25/reply-all</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;iframe scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;152&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; allow=&quot;encrypted-media&quot; src=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/6KpdRYyMSoqYda3DgqGEdg&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Open Letter on Diversity & Inclusion at Scaling Bitcoin</title>
   <link href="/blog/2017/09/27/scaling-diversity-and-inclusion/"/>
   <updated>2017-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/blog/2017/09/27/scaling-diversity-and-inclusion</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We started &lt;a href=&quot;https://scalingbitcoin.org&quot;&gt;Scaling Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt; with a deep commitment to diversity and inclusion.
Fundamentally, Scaling Bitcoin is about bringing together elements of the
Bitcoin community that would not otherwise – many of the core contributors met
face to face for the first time in Montreal. Meeting face to face was a
fantastic opportunity to bridge divides and seek common goals; at Scaling
Bitcoin spontaneous discussions broke out which would have never occurred
online. Diversity and inclusion are key elements in pulling together different
parts of our community to have the discussions fruitfully. Fundamentally
Scaling Bitcoin exists to work towards eliminating any barrier to entry for any
person to contribute to Bitcoin’s scientific and engineering ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diversity and inclusion are complicated multi-faceted topics – at Scaling
Bitcoin, we do our best to address them from all sides. Our conference aspires
to be in a different region every time, from our first event in Montreal, to
Hong Kong, to Milan, and now, to Silicon Valley. Our participants and sponsors
come from all over the world (18 countries at the last event!), speak many
different languages, and have vastly different perspectives on how we’ll
accomplish our shared goal of Scaling Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We help people attend Scaling Bitcoin who would not be able to otherwise as a
part of our diversity and inclusion efforts. This help comes in multiple forms,
including discounted tickets for students, as well as travel and accommodation
assistance for those who require it. Our chief concern is getting the
individuals most likely to contribute to Bitcoin’s scientific and engineering
ecosystem to the conference. We also try to help those who face additional
difficulties to better integrate into the community. In past Scaling Bitcoins,
this has included efforts and special programming through our academic
supporting organizations to better socially integrate low-income, minority, and
female participants at Scaling Bitcoin. For example, at Milan one of our
Academic partners (&lt;a href=&quot;http://dci.mit.edu&quot;&gt;The MIT DCI&lt;/a&gt;) hosted a special dinner for the students from
their summer bootcamp (&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/mit-media-lab-digital-currency-initiative/apply-now-mit-intro-to-cryptocurrencies-bootcamp-for-underrepresented-minorities-and-women-ba85fa8fc898&quot;&gt;you can read about it
here&lt;/a&gt;)
to get to interact with some core developers in a smaller group setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin developers and scientists don’t just materialize overnight, it requires
diligent study and effort. This is an intimidating prospect for almost anyone,
and many capable developers drop out for lack of good support. Initiatives like
&lt;a href=&quot;http://chaincode.com&quot;&gt;Chaincode&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://bluematt.bitcoin.ninja/2016/08/08/chaincode/&quot;&gt;Hacker
Residency&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dglab.com/en/&quot;&gt;DGLAB&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://bc-2.jp/&quot;&gt;BC2&lt;/a&gt; workshop have been
wildly successful in nurturing talented Bitcoin Core Developers. Scaling
Bitcoin is simply doing our part to onboard more talent. Explicitly seeking to
onboard talent from diverse backgrounds is a critical for engineering Bitcoin
to be an empowering technology to meet the needs of users all over the world.
The last several decades of research on the subject shows that seeking out
social diversity leads to better decision-making across the board (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-diversity-makes-us-smarter/&quot;&gt;read about
the research
here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, as a part of our efforts to improve Scaling Bitcoin by better
structuring our Planning Committee we created a Diversity &amp;amp; Inclusion
Committee. This committee is comprised of individuals who were excited to help
us to continue our efforts around diversity and inclusion. One of the main
tasks for this committee is to help us review and process subsidy requests,
which are awarded based on many factors, including, likelihood of contributing
to Bitcoin’s scientific and engineering ecosystem, demonstrated need, and total
cost (we have a limited budget, after all). Despite now having an explicit
committee for diversity and inclusion, it continues to be the job of every
volunteer in Scaling Bitcoin to work towards eliminating any barrier to entry
for any person to contribute to Bitcoin’s scientific and engineering ecosystem.
Different people experience different barriers to entry to a field like
Bitcoin, thus, the kinds of support programs we offer are not always available
to everyone (we can’t afford to give everyone student ticket pricing!). The
Diversity &amp;amp; Inclusion Committee is there to ensure that our efforts are fair
and sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology conferences like Scaling Bitcoin present a remarkable opportunity
for building community. In light of recent reports of incidents of harassment
and exclusionary practices at tech conferences, we’ve take a progressive stance
on making sure that Scaling Bitcoin remains a respectful and safe space for all
of our participants to build that community. Incidents of harassment and
exclusionary practices negatively impact people of all genders, races, and
backgrounds, as well as the conferences and their communities. We take such
issues seriously and have required all participants to follow our &lt;a href=&quot;https://scalingbitcoin.org/code-of-conduct&quot;&gt;Code of
Conduct&lt;/a&gt; since the first Scaling Bitcoin event in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of what makes Scaling Bitcoin such a remarkable gathering is the intense
level of focus on the technology during the event. Our CoC exists to minimize
the possibility of distractions and to maximize the learning, shared
understanding and technical advancement of one of the most important
engineering projects of our time. We hope that our attendees recognize and
support that objective, and the organizing committee will as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the Program Committee, which handles talk selection, operates
with complete autonomy from the rest of the Scaling Bitcoin organization,
including the Diversity &amp;amp; Inclusion Committee. No one is excluded from the
conference as a result of our diversity and inclusion efforts. The main goal of
the Program Committee is to unbiasedly select talks with the highest potential
impact on Bitcoin. The majority of tickets are sold openly to the public. We
welcome any suggestions and ideas from the Bitcoin community as to how our
efforts can be more effective and we will continue to do our best to make
Bitcoin a more diverse and inclusive environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to be hosting what we expect to be the best Scaling Bitcoin yet
this year. To increase our reach and impact in the community, we’re hosting a 2
Day tutorial preceding Scaling Bitcoin called Dev++. This is a wonderful
opportunity for those just entering the space to get fast-paced high-quality
instruction on becoming a Bitcoin Engineer. Following the conference, we will
have a Career Fair and an event for startups to pitch to investors. You can
read more about these new initiatives at
&lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoinedge.org&quot;&gt;BitcoinEdge.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeremy Rubin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scaling Bitcoin Planning Committee&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With special thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/byrongibson&quot;&gt;Byron Gibson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/neha&quot;&gt;Neha
Narula&lt;/a&gt;, and the rest of the Scaling Bitcoin Planning
Committee for reviewing and editing this letter, and for maintaining a strong
commitment to diversity and inclusion in Bitcoin.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>United States Government Censorship of Fuck Nazis Virtual Lapel Pin</title>
   <link href="/blog/2017/09/01/usg-censorship-fuck-nazis/"/>
   <updated>2017-09-01T00:10:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/blog/2017/09/01/usg-censorship-fuck-nazis</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I woke up in the morning of September 1st, 2017 I immediately began my
morning ritual of lazily glancing through emails.  On this morning, one
particular email stood out — the Fuck Nazis Virtual
Lapel Pin had been censored by the United States Government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s jump back a minute for some context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On August 19th, 2017 I began a new project, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://fucknazis.us&quot;&gt;Fuck Nazis Virtual Lapel
Pin&lt;/a&gt;. The project’s goal was to raise funds to resist the
recent uptick in Nazism and other forms of violent racist extremism in America.
The Fuck Nazis Virtual Lapel Pin is a unique fund-raiser because donors
quid-pro-quo receive a digital asset in return for their contribution, I hoped
this would harness the excitement around the emerging &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/ib_coinofferings&quot;&gt;“Initial Coin
Offering”&lt;/a&gt;
phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reception was not as positive as I had hoped it would be — earlier in
the week, I had been subject to some minor &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2017/09/01/ethereum-censorship-fuck-nazis/&quot;&gt;censorship by the Ethereum
Maintainers and Community Moderators&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On September 1st, 2017 at 2:40 AM Pacific Daylight Time Neustar initiated a
transfer of my domain. One hour and 29 minutes later Neustar sent me an email
explaining the transfer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/fucknazis.us/unauth-transfer.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Takedown&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/fucknazis.us/explanation.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Takedown&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve sent Neustar an email requesting that they reinstate my registration, but I’ve not yet heard back from them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/fucknazis.us/reinstate-me.png&quot; alt=&quot;Request to Reinstate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neustar is a contractor hired by the U.S. Governemnt to operate the .us TLD.
Because they are managing a federally owned property, I beleive they are
obligated to follow the First Amendment with respect to registered names.
Otherwise, I do not think the FCC may legally continue to use them as a
contractor. To quote
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.icannwatch.org/article.pl?sid=02/04/25/082532&quot;&gt;ICANNWatch&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[W]hile a private entity like Neustar is under no intrinsic obligation to
respect the First Amendment, the fact that they did this under government
consultation, and pursuant to a government-granted charter to operate the
country code registry for the United States, raises serious issues of
Constitutionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not a strange expectation to hold that contractors of the United States
Government must abide by constitutional provisions. For instance, private
prisons are not at liberty to exact cruel and unusual punishments. Kimberly N.
Brown delivers a thorough treatment of this in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.repository.law.indiana.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=11083&amp;amp;context=ilj&quot;&gt;“We the People,” Constitutional
Accountability, and Outsourcing
Government&lt;/a&gt;.
While there are controversial cases, it is generally clear that public actors
must hold accountable private actors that they delegate their constitutional
powers to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notwithstanding the concern over whether it is the FCC or Neustar who is
legally culpable, we can safely assume that the FCC is bound to ensure that
Neustar respects constitutional rights in fulfilling their duties as a
government contractor, and therefore examine Neustar as a government actor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neustar’s management policy document can be found
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ntia.doc.gov/files/ntia/publications/ustld2007_07_b_services.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
The relevant sections are B-78 and B-98. Neustar claims that they will &lt;em&gt;review&lt;/em&gt;
domains which contain the “7 Words” and possibly delete them (presumably,
ensuring that they are not violating the registrant’s First Amendment rights).
Their claim is that the domain &lt;a href=&quot;https://fucknazis.us&quot;&gt;fucknazis.us&lt;/a&gt; violate’s
the “7 Words” policy enforced by Neustar. (This is a reference to George
Carlin’s infamous &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seven_dirty_words&quot;&gt;Seven Dirty
Words&lt;/a&gt; skit) In this case, the
presence of “fuck” in the domain is what alerted Neustar to need to review my
domain.  However, in failing to waive &lt;a href=&quot;https://fucknazis.us&quot;&gt;fucknazis.us&lt;/a&gt; I
believe they violated my First Amendment rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three major relevant Supreme Court cases here,  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.law.cornell.edu/supremecourt/text/403/15&quot;&gt;Cohen v. California
(1971)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.law.cornell.edu/supremecourt/text/413/15&quot;&gt;Miller v.
California (1973)&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href=&quot;https://supreme.justia.com/cases/federal/us/438/726/case.html&quot;&gt;FCC v. Pacifica Foundation (1978)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Cohen v. California, a man was arrested for disturbing the peace for wearing
a “Fuck the Draft” shirt. In this case, the speech was found to be protected by 
the First Amendment for multiple reasons. Most relevantly, the court refused to recognize
the speech as “Fighting Words”, or speech intended to elicit violence. This is because
Cohen’s voiced dissent of the draft was not intended to elicit any violence, it was simply
to voice an opinion. Similarly, the material published on the Fuck Nazis site was
clearly in support of non-violent action, e.g.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As a first measure, and irrespective of what is most effective, I want to use
funds raised ensure that it is possible to protest these Nazis as safely as
possible. No one should permit the Nazis to intimidate them out of their
freedom to speak against them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;along with a list of other non-violent actions I would use the funds raised to
support. The court went further to find that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Finally, and in the same vein, we cannot indulge the facile assumption that
one can forbid particular words without also running a substantial risk of
suppressing ideas in the process. Indeed, governments might soon seize upon
the censorship of particular words as a convenient guise for banning the
expression of unpopular views. We have been able, as noted above, to discern
little social benefit that might result from running the risk of opening the
door to such grave results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes it clear that the censorship of Fuck Nazis Virtual Lapel Pins by revocation
of the domain &lt;a href=&quot;https://fucknazis.us&quot;&gt;fucknazis.us&lt;/a&gt; is unconstitutional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miller v. California is a case of a very different nature involving the
distribution of pornographic content, but it established a simple three-prong
test for unprotected explicit speech. If you pass all three tests, then the work
is considered obscene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(a) whether “the average person, applying contemporary community standards”
would find that the work, taken as a whole, appeals to the prurient interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fail: Fuck Nazis is clearly non-pornographic and elicits no sexual response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(b) whether the work depicts or describes, in a patently
offensive way, sexual conduct specifically defined by the applicable state
law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fail: Fuck Nazis is clearly non-sexual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(c) whether the work, taken as a whole, lacks serious literary,
artistic, political, or scientific value. If a state obscenity law is thus
limited, First Amendment values are adequately protected by ultimate
independent appellate review of constitutional claims when necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fail: Fuck Nazis is a political and artistic project, and is presented cogently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having &lt;em&gt;clearly&lt;/em&gt; failed all three tests, Fuck Nazis is non-obscene protected
speech by all measures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Critically, both Cohen v. California and Miller v. California are both rulings
with regards to the state’s ability to restrict speech. Only FCC v. Pacifica
Foundation deals with the federal government’s ability to restrict “obscene”
speech, which established the “7 Dirty Words”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The critically relevant part of FCC v. Pacifica Foundation is that the measures
enforce by the FCC (to only broadcast during hours children are unlikely to be
awake) did not prevent adults from accessing and finding the content. In this
case, Neustar’s actions against Fuck Nazis does prevent adults from accessing
the content unadulterated (whereas the time restriction enforced by the FCC
permitted identical material to be broadcast at a reasonably later time).
Furthermore, based on Neustar’s enforced policies I would be able to register
the domain “nazis.us” (if it were available — it’s been held since 2014)
and use the subdomain “fuck” giving me the “fuck.nazis.us” domain. This makes
the case that there is zero benefit from the measure taken by Neustar, at the
expense of the significant burden of forcing me to change a domain that I have
already linked to in numerous communications. Of greater concern is the general
freedom of speech risk established by this enforcement mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the above, Neustar, acting as an agent of the United States
government, plainly violated my First Amendment rights causing damages to my project
that are difficult to quantify given that  the fund-raiser I was hosting on the site is
ongoing.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Censorship by Ethereum Maintainers</title>
   <link href="/blog/2017/09/01/ethereum-censorship-fuck-nazis/"/>
   <updated>2017-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/blog/2017/09/01/ethereum-censorship-fuck-nazis</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Ethereum Maintainers and Moderators inexplicably took actions to censor the
Fuck Nazis Virtual Lapel Pin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I posted the project to the Ethereum subreddit on August 26th
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/ethereum/comments/6w9vd0/announcing_the_fuck_nazis_virtual_lapel_pin_sale/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)
it faced an immediate barrage of negative attention from the Ethereum
community. I can tolerate negative reception, but I can’t tolerate
censorship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the negative response I noticed a few days after posting was Vitalik
Buterin (the infamous founder and lead maintainer of Ethereum) liking a
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/ethereum/comments/6w9vd0/announcing_the_fuck_nazis_virtual_lapel_pin_sale/&quot;&gt;libelous
tweet&lt;/a&gt;
which called my project “a shameless attempt at scamming people”. I typically
interpret a like on Twitter as at least a weak endorsement (the twitter-meme
“RT not endorsement” can be taken to imply that while retweeting is not
endorsement, maybe liking is).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/avsa/status/902163764258144257&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/fucknazis.us/vitalik-scam.png&quot; alt=&quot;Vitalik likes a libelous tweet&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my perspective, Vitalik’s implicit endorsement of a libelous
message claiming that I am perpetrating fraud with Fuck Nazis is the only
shame-worthy action! From day one Fuck Nazis’ course of action has been
focused on many charitable causes, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Donations to organizations like the Southern Poverty Law Center and the Anti-Defamation League.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sponsoring guards for synagogues who are denied publicly funded police details.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Workshops on how to non-violently oppose Nazis in cities where they are staging demonstrations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Vitalik liked the above tweet, I noticed that my post was censored
from &lt;a href=&quot;https://reddit.com/r/ethereum&quot;&gt;/r/ethereum&lt;/a&gt; by the moderators (Vitalik is
also the lead moderator of /r/ethereum). This censorship occured days after it
had been on the front page, leading me to believe it was removed for no logical
reason other than distaste for the issue involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/ethereum/search?q=Fuck+Nazis&amp;amp;restrict_sr=on&amp;amp;sort=relevance&amp;amp;t=all&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/fucknazis.us/eth-censored.png&quot; alt=&quot;Removed from /r/ethereum&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met Vitalik back in 2014, in the very early days of Ethereum, so I was
willing to give him the benefit of the doubt on the post removal. I shot him an
email on August 29th and again on the 31st but he is yet to respond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/fucknazis.us/reddit-mod.png&quot; alt=&quot;No Response&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His lack of response to me signals, but does not confirm, that it was him who
 censored Fuck Nazis and he is unwilling to justify his actions to me directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ethereum Foundation and affiliated contributors have no legal requirement to grant me
free speech as a private organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, they do have a moral responsibility to protect free speech and to be
inclusive of many different kinds of people within their community. By actively
censoring my post on Fuck Nazis, they have chosen to signal their alignment
with a racist agenda and cause a chilling effect on future social impact
projects on Ethereum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their attempted censorship runs counter to the philosophy stated on
&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethereum.org&quot;&gt;ethereum.org&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Ethereum is a  decentralized platform that runs smart contracts: applications
that run exactly as programmed without any possibility of downtime,
censorship, fraud or third party interference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While certainly Reddit doesn’t attempt to make the same censorship guarantees
as Ethereum, it’s difficult to imagine that if the leader of the development
team behind Ethereum is engaged in censoring causes spitefully on Reddit that
he will lead the team to fulfill the promises laid out in their statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vitalik (and others in the Ethereum Foundation) must make clear their strong
intention for building inclusive and tolerant community with explicit actions
to improve the situation. Until sufficiently addressed, the entire community
must continually push leaders of the Ethereum community for more information
on how they plan to treat similar issues in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t about getting an apology for censoring the Fuck Nazis thread, it’s
about not building technologies that put power into the hands of hateful
people who will use their power to infringe on your human rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, this is the least of my worries currently: the Fuck Nazis Virtual
Lapel Pin project is currently facing &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2017/09/01/usg-censorship-fuck-nazis/&quot;&gt;ongoing censorship from the U.S.
Goverment&lt;/a&gt; as well. But I figured
it was worthwhile for me to write up this post so that the Ethereum community can
respond accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Perfunctory Tokens for Public Works</title>
   <link href="/talks/2017/07/24/perfunctory-tokens/"/>
   <updated>2017-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/talks/2017/07/24/perfunctory-tokens</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk at the Digital Garage New Context Conference in Tokyo about “Perfunctory Tokens”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s presented as a set of opinions I’m thinking through about with regards to the emergent ICO phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/228186350&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/228186350/4fe319322c&quot;&gt;NCC 2017 TOKYO/ DAY 2 Blockchain SESSION 3 TALK：Perfunctory Tokens &amp;amp; Public Works&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Drawing the Blockchain</title>
   <link href="/blog/2017/02/25/correct-blockchain-pointers/"/>
   <updated>2017-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/blog/2017/02/25/correct-blockchain-pointers</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/bitcoin/blockchainpointers.png&quot; alt=&quot;This is correct&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my major pet peeves in presentations about the blockchain is that most
people seem to draw the arrows/pointers in the incorrect direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pointers should point from newer blocks to older blocks. This is because in a
blockchain, each block is immutable so it would be impossible to update older
blocks to point to newer ones. This is also in line with most singly linked
list representations. Because it can be confusing, it’s always best to include
reference heights for extra clarity.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Kansai Trip</title>
   <link href="/blog/2017/02/09/kansai-trip/"/>
   <updated>2017-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/blog/2017/02/09/kansai-trip</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post got backlogged, so just putting it up unfinished. Will backfill pictures when I find them later.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a few day reprieve from Tokyo to visit the Kansai prefecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there, I visited Osaka and Nara. I was feeling a little bit unwell so
I skipped Kyoto/Kobe, but will be looking forward to visiting when I’m next
in Japan!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-to-kansai&quot;&gt;Getting to Kansai&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to take an early morning Shinkansen (i.e. a bullet train) from Tokyo
to Osaka on Tuesday morning. Because my hotel stay was officially over, I
stayed the night in a “Manga Kissaten”. For the uninitiated, a Manga Kissa is
basically a somewhat skeevy 24/7 pay-per-hour library with free drinks and
private booths. I had heard that they were a reasonable place to stay – I
think I had a particularly bad one, the air was smoke filled, the drinks were
just OK, there was no shower in the morning, and they didn’t dim the lights
past midnight (these are all problems I’ve heard higher-end Manga Kissaten do
not suffer). Blearly eyed, I made my way to the train station and purchased a
ticket, and boarded the first train to Osaka.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;Shinkansen! Shinkansen!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;osaka&quot;&gt;Osaka&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon arriving in Osaka I made my way down to a place called Spa World in an area
called Dotonbori-Mae. Unfortunately, they were overbooked/expensive so I looked
elsewhere nearby. After comparing the offerings across the street, I found a
really nice backpacker’s hostel where I was able to secure a private room
(Japanese style) for about $13 USD a night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;Selfie in the hostel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the hostel I decided to just walk the length of the city, starting from the
hostel all the way to Umeda. As a straight shot, this is about 4 miles, but I
wandered around so it was longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For lunch I ate okonomiyaki (a Japanese “pizza” that’s a little closer to a
omelette). It is served on a hot griddle, yum!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later that night I went to the Don Quixote. DQ is like a wacky Walmart/Spencer’s
Gifts hybrid. It has everything from groceries to a sex shop. A few floors up
there was an (unrelated?) arcade/casino. I bought some chips and started playing
games. After playing for about an hour (and not doing very well), I went to cash
out my remaining tokens. I found out that tokens are not actually exchangeable
for &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt;. I asked some other players if they could help me exchange, and
they agreed because they thought you could cash out too. When they found out
they couldn’t, they seemed to be a little off put, but I gave them my tokens so
they were happy. What was weird is they even had a bank for the tokens…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;Token bank&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nara&quot;&gt;Nara&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed my visit to Nara. The deer are so kawaii!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Nara you can find the Tōdai-ji, or a temple featuring a huge bronze Buddha
(the largest bronze statue in the world and the largest Buddha in Japan). The
Tōdai-ji temple is also one of the largest wooden buildings in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Interview by Shin'ichiro Matsuo on Bitcoin Development</title>
   <link href="/talks/2017/02/01/matsuo-interview/"/>
   <updated>2017-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/talks/2017/02/01/matsuo-interview</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here’s a few cuts of an interview from when I taught at &lt;a href=&quot;https://bc-2.jp/season1/&quot;&gt;BC-2 Workshop Winter 2017&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aycec_N59b8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xGZVUnav8eU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HCoFQybzIbo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Introduction to Bitcoin Development</title>
   <link href="/talks/2017/02/01/intro-bitcoin-dev-jp/"/>
   <updated>2017-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/talks/2017/02/01/intro-bitcoin-dev-jp</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here’s an introduction to Bitcoin Core Development I gave at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bc-2.jp/season1/&quot;&gt;BC-2 Workshop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bitcoin Development process&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIP) Process&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Performance improvement walk through&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;iframe webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/215140673&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bc-2.jp/archive/season1/materials/0104_performace.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF of slides here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Visiting Japan</title>
   <link href="/blog/2017/01/28/japan/"/>
   <updated>2017-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/blog/2017/01/28/japan</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m visiting Japan for two weeks to help teach &lt;a href=&quot;https://bc-2.jp&quot;&gt;BC-2&lt;/a&gt; at
Digital Garage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very excited to have the chance to explore Tokyo and hope to make many new
friends while out here!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully I can fill in a few details about my trip as I go…&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Structuring Multi Transaction Contracts in Bitcoin</title>
   <link href="/talks/2017/01/26/multi-txn-contracts/"/>
   <updated>2017-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/talks/2017/01/26/multi-txn-contracts</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was asked to give a talk at Stanford Cyber Initiative’s Blockchain Protocol
Analysis and Security Engineering 2017 conference on some of my forthcoming
research. While it’s still a bit green, I was excited to share some of the work I’d
been doing on multi-transaction contracts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/public/pdfs/multi-txn-contracts.pdf&quot;&gt;Slides Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Contributing to Bitcoin</title>
   <link href="/talks/2016/11/01/dg-contributing-to-bitcoin/"/>
   <updated>2016-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/talks/2016/11/01/dg-contributing-to-bitcoin</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk at the Digital Garage New Context Conference San Francisco on how to begin contributing to Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/public/pdfs/ContributeToBitcoin.pdf&quot;&gt;Slides Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>tail -f /var/log/life</title>
   <link href="/blog/2016/08/23/first/"/>
   <updated>2016-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/blog/2016/08/23/first</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m hoping to start blogging more frequently – consider this the first post.
I’m going to fill in some back-dated posts though.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Graduating MIT</title>
   <link href="/blog/2016/06/03/graduation/"/>
   <updated>2016-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/blog/2016/06/03/graduation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/nerdy.png&quot; alt=&quot;I'm the biggest nerd&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I did it: I graduated MIT with my S.B. and M.Eng in 4 years! And
apparently I was the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.boston.com/culture/education/2016/06/03/8-joyously-nerdy-occurrences-mit-commencement&quot;&gt;most
joyously nerdy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Improving the Bitcoin Development Process</title>
   <link href="/talks/2016/03/06/improving-bitcoin-dev/"/>
   <updated>2016-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/talks/2016/03/06/improving-bitcoin-dev</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OGIMXTtD0Sk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Probabalistic Payments in Bitcoin using OP_SIZE</title>
   <link href="/musings/2015/11/26/probpay/"/>
   <updated>2015-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/musings/2015/11/26/probpay</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I designed a mechanism that allows for probabilistic payments in Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The foundation of the mechanism is sane, where it veers out of “sanity” is in
the attempts to get it to work well off-chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I originally wrote this paper on November 26th, 2015, and circulated it among a
few colleagues. I think this is the first use case of OP_SIZE to implement XOR
fair coin flipping, although &lt;a href=&quot;http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/6956580/?reload=true&amp;amp;arnumber=6956580&quot;&gt;Secure Multiparty Computations on
Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt;
has similar elements and it was discussed on IRC in #bitcoin-wizards that
OP_SIZE might enable probabilistic payments, but not specifically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am first posting it on my website as of March 11th, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/public/pdfs/probpay.pdf&quot;&gt;full text here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Scaling Bitcoin</title>
   <link href="/blog/2015/09/11/scaling-bitcoin-mtl/"/>
   <updated>2015-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/blog/2015/09/11/scaling-bitcoin-mtl</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m honored to be serving as Program Chair for the first ever Scaling Bitcoin in Montreal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://scalingbitcoin.org/montreal2015/#location&quot;&gt;More Info&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Returning Home</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/07/27/sz-adventure-51/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/07/27/sz-adventure-51</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, my travels in Asia are over. What better way to wrap things up
than to make tea ceremony with mom and take photos on a shenzhen-selfie stick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/nhju1iddy6wmr9c/IMG_1300.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/dikp5tyzoqdcpbp/IMG_1310.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Jasmine Rice Factory Tour</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/07/14/sz-adventure-38/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/07/14/sz-adventure-38</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Note the change of location!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I was in Thailand visiting my friend there; I had the fortune of being
able to visit his family’s rice processing factory. They’re basically the
world’s largest Thai Jasmine Rice processing company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/9ln625lh861e7pw/IMG_1077.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
That’s a lot of rice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unprocessed rice comes in like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/x12eof3n7ogz53x/IMG_1069.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Lots of random stuff mixed in…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The junk gets removed in big gravity sifters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/poui33yaj2dcg3r/IMG_1067.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Gravity Sifting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/vfnlnfr67f9q9cn/IMG_1064.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Look at that junk!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rice is then polished…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/h7c260vx6o91af0/IMG_1056.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
An array of polishers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/aw698mu1f84ng27/IMG_1057.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Shiny!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, an electronic separator uses jets of air to eliminate non rice things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/vr22y9ri1zob6ek/riceblower.gif?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
This uses some fancy machine vision to detect rice/non-rice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The finished products&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/b3slhse3otj5922/IMG_1073.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Shown are two different grades of rice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;science&quot;&gt;Science!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also some cool stuff going on to make sure the rice is of the right quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/v5aouwdqb0uuccl/IMG_1084.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Spectrophotometer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rice-o-meter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/mivfkt9hap6p0gu/IMG_1100.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Measures transparency, whiteness, and the milling degree to judge quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were several other tests as well, including an amylose test.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Smell Clock</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/07/06/sz-adventure-30/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/07/06/sz-adventure-30</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The smell clock is a device I built for the Shenzhen manufacturing bootcamp. While we were there,
we had a challenge to build a prototype on a tight budget. The assignment was to build something
that could denote the passage of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided, while walking around the market, that these little bottle top humidifiers were really cool:
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/js3k86kf9574e89/IMG_0293.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I knew I had to incorporate them. I walked around the market scoping out
prices and couldn’t find them for a good deal.  Just when I was about to give
up, I found them at a price I could afford – if I recall it was a few dollars
a piece, but I needed a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/gtpkrgtlxk4hjtg/IMG_0294.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I laser cut a case for each humidifier out of acrylic and opened up each humidifier and attached a wire
to trigger the toggle switch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/3y5zyd1433yddp2/IMG_0296.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order for it to look nice, I needed some good looking bottles, so I hit the grocery store, where I found:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/xm58idnqu2o6de1/IMG_0915.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
A bicycle built from toothpaste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t find any nice bottles, so I ended up using some ugly ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design uses 4x4 grid of individually controllable humidifiers connected to an arduino mega. Each of the bottle is filled with different fragrances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/dbhpdkn5x00uyrc/IMG_0916.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up running into trouble with the plastic case, so I cut a new one from wood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the finished product:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/x2p6e8yox5xcmzm/smell-demo-large2.gif?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Wirebonding Factory Tour</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/07/01/sz-adventure-25.2/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/07/01/sz-adventure-25.2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wirebonding is a technique you’re probably familiar with if you’ve ever taken
apart a cheap toy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a slightly harder technique to employ than using a standard packaged chip,
but if employed correctly can help reduce cost (raw die is cheaper), footprint,
and weight. The cost per wire is really small!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, rather than solder a chip down, you paste it down and then solder a
small wire from the chip die to the board and then cover it in goop to protect
it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This technique used to be really hard to access, but with more automation costs
have come down drastically making this an interesting technique for a
cost-concious engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The factory boss here was a very friendly lady, and she gave us an awesome tour!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/7idk63gzj0b3eh1/IMG_0858.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Example of a finished wire bonded board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A worker, by hand, places the tiny raw dies onto the circuit boards using little wooden chopsticks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/5in5azgdcvy6foy/IMG_0836.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
The dies are really tiny to be working with by hand!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An employee configures the machine. In the upper left, you can see a wiring
diagram, as well as a computer showing the current alignment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/lit9vwvz6apcu4o/IMG_0846.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wirebonding machine drops small conductive wires from the bond points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/7p2zduixs0tjp3b/wirebond.gif?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Go! Go! Go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After wire bonding:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/5svqtylo4wd5ajh/IMG_0844.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Ok… maybe this is before, I can’t recall. The wires are hard to see…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is a mistake, a worker uses a machine to correct it. The machine has
knobs which scale each human movement down by a factor of 10. This allows them
to do the detailed work needed to operate on these tiny wires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/tuqbu24x3t336mt/manual.jpg?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, the boards have protective goop placed on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/m0bq2b06syh9d3n/goop.gif?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Goop laying machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boards then go into an oven to cure the goop to a hard shell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They can also do clear goops!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Manual Board Population/SMT Factory Tour</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/07/01/sz-adventure-25.1/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/07/01/sz-adventure-25.1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When you make a lot of a board, you get a fully automated SMT line. But what about when you only make 5?
Programming a SMT line takes time and is expensive. So you can do the dumb thing – do them by hand!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, even though the components are tiny the employees are highly skilled with surgically precise hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re getting hand done SMT, it’s obviously at a smaller scale, so things
are a bit more laid back you could say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/omlavw0mnkm2y8h/randomcat.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
E.g., there was a random cat hanging out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, schematics and PCBs come in and are marked up to help the workers place parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/47el1bsuhkyoxsn/schematic_study.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Silk screens get made to put the solder paste down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/cffmqpvdjhvc31m/silksolder.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parts get carefully placed onto the boards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/m4xw75dawjjuddz/twezeplace.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workers have really steady hands :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/xtdvdaf5v973ucs/place.gif?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, as with any SMT process, the boards get sent to the oven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/i6zjirhf6lg6gpo/reflowoven.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>South China Material City Tour</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/30/sz-adventure-24/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/30/sz-adventure-24</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;With my back still in significant pain from the previous nights massages, it
was time for the South China Material City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The South China Material City is an industrial region situated in Shenzhen where
you can go to get raw goods or materials in bulk quantity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/pe99swsejv3f2kx/IMG_0736.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s basically a big outdoor mall where you can go into one of many vendors and find
anything you need, from gears to leather. Everyone is very hospitable and there were
offers of tea at some of the shops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/5alzmgi03jn0oja/IMG_0737.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was also some (very large) indoor malls, with lots of outlet priced goods:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/61p9nsapibey9tk/IMG_0813.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was also some more random stuff, like people drying spices on their shop fronts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/1oiqz8prz4cz3t0/IMG_0750.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/xb0pbzy3mne6dil/IMG_0751.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or a seemingly abandoned amusement park:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/86sti4p15o45czi/IMG_0768.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/7lxft6pugcddvmc/IMG_0769.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/yyhrne3gc63krkl/IMG_0770.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/d05v92kauyawctq/IMG_0771.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/nmzmveshn6myfvm/IMG_0772.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/78eakighro1mia6/IMG_0764.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/8jaku73dmlpfy79/IMG_0765.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You really could find anything there, from chemical supplies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/x1bhs6lq2xpf1zi/IMG_0801.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/z2ehw64l2wx74am/IMG_0803.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/ud32t1jguhh4odg/IMG_0805.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To raw plastics used for cables (something like $10/25 kg):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/fl06u60rblp14hc/IMG_0797.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/0onfhadfb0k1rqg/IMG_0799.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To clips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/7o9a6f82jjjd1ut/IMG_0784.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/y44tfirjrc2d0k7/IMG_0788.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/4k2hyo2u8cixq5y/IMG_0785.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
That one is absurd – knives on carabiner clips to cut your rope?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leathers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/bqphxz7ml4bqs0f/IMG_0760.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creepy Leathers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/pscban3cvdh8rtx/IMG_0789.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/t8hbnyby3ozmo9j/IMG_0761.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sewing machines – from new, to very old:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/wdfaygbnz71bple/IMG_0762.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/xzlfi1uycas0rf3/IMG_0773.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tile carvers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/bkelzr8tbwg2ncx/IMG_0743.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/i5zfudzkrz1pn1b/IMG_0747.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Papercraft store where you can get nice boxes made:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/2ce8tfe6mpwtpz4/IMG_0729.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/mz2hlmuh4bbckvz/IMG_0731.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, there was cool finished good store with lots of cool electronics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/v1gyocpe0y30bjr/IMG_0810.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/tyzcdbwpcsgenna/IMG_0808.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, one of the funniest parts of the South China Material City was all the
samples people were willing to give for free.  I got clips, bracelets, ropes,
fabrics, and many other things for free or very cheap. I almost made it into a
game to see if I could get something at every vendor I stopped by. The odd
thing is that when I contacted one of the suppliers to buy more bracelets (as
gifts for my return) they never got back to me!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Chinese Massage Parlor</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/29/sz-adventure-23.2/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/29/sz-adventure-23.2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the evening of the 23rd, we took a trip over to a local massage parlor.
Before you crack any jokes about what goes on in the massage parlor (yes, that
does still exist if you want to find it), that’s not why we went to the massage
parlor. We went to kick back Shenzhen Style! No photos of this trip, for better
or for worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The massage parlor is kind of like a rest and relaxation hotel. You can stay
there all night if you want to. When we showed up, we had to give the
receptionist passports in accordance with Chinese law for overnight stays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you get to the parlor, you split off by gender, and then you take a
shower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, there’s a large public bath (naked!) where you can go to enjoy some cool
refreshing water, ice cold water, and steamy hot water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following your dip in the public bath, you get a robe and slippers and head on
over to the main massage area. Here, you get a huge comfy recliner chair, the
kind you could easily sleep in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, a host comes over and offers you the menu, where you can order various
beverages (such as watermelon juice or beer) and massages. Bunnie was trying to
order a green tea for a very long time, because he kept on accidentally saying
road fork (they both sound like “lu cha”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically you start off with some light treatments, such as a foot massage or,
if you’re feeling like it, an ear scrape (I wasn’t bold enough so I stuck to
    the foot massage). Then, you can get a larger treatment if you like, your
    choice of different varieties of back massage, such as a Traditional
    Chinese Medicine or Thai Oil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was told it was the most traditional was indeed the Traditional Chinese
Medicine Massage, I opted for that. A few minutes later, some doctors (of the
tcm variety) came to us and led us to the massage tables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I want to reserve my language somewhat, especially when it comes to
experiencing another culture, but FUCK EVERYTHING ABOUT THE TCM MASSAGE. It was
horrible, horrible pain for like an hour. The doctor systematically found every
pain and pressure point in my back and body and dug and jabbed them
mercilessly. As I squealed in pain, the doctor only laughed and prodded more.
If I had any secrets I’m sure he could have gotten me to reveal them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the rest of the week, my back was in pretty awful pain. I don’t think I’ll
be back for a TCM massage again, but I’d go back for a Thai Oil Massage (that’s
what you normally think of when you hear “massage”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the massage, there are some other facilities (such as ping pong) to hang
out and relax with, but I think I was too much in pain to want to take
advantage of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the massage parlor is a pretty good deal. For about 300RMB (around
~$50 USD) you get an overnight place to stay as well as massages and
entertainment. Would definitely recommend it for your trip out to Shenzhen, but
avoid the TCM massage.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Furniture Factory Tour</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/29/sz-adventure-23.1/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/29/sz-adventure-23.1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For Day 23 we’re going to take a look at a furniture factory. This is a HUGE
factory; probably the largest we saw on our trip, spanning many many hangars.
Unfortunately I didn’t take too many pictures at this factory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We start our journey in the furniture factory with some basic processing of raw materials:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/1rla5prdm66209y/IMG_0655.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beams get cut up into little pieces and glued together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/54v0tdivv34w3sn/glue-tiny.gif?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/nywbc868vkjqr01/IMG_0661.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
All done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did I mention that it’s a large factory?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/ukg22y2ba9qqb6j/IMG_0662.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;distressingpainting&quot;&gt;Distressing/Painting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/nezrhonea04itec/IMG_0684.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;two-kinds-of-leg&quot;&gt;Two Kinds of Leg&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wooden-leg&quot;&gt;Wooden Leg&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/rj7q6v1z3ar5p2z/IMG_0677.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/i57152dke4fwpki/IMG_0678.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;resin-leg&quot;&gt;Resin Leg&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/g2whlscnjqkkqoy/IMG_0714.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/pyxn805qqhw0w3d/IMG_0722.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shipping&quot;&gt;Shipping&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/sqjri5wqvqm6jk2/IMG_0720.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;showroom&quot;&gt;Showroom&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They make a lot of varieties of furniture!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/nsihxm7plpoa0jz/IMG_0643.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These gorgeous wood tables are all for domestic market! Too big to ship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/5laeqta95wqbpk5/IMG_0646.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Precision Casting Factory Tour</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/26/sz-adventure-20.2/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/26/sz-adventure-20.2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The precision casting plant was really neat! They have some pretty major
clients, which you might be able to guess from some of the photos (but probably best
if this doesn’t show up in the search results).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This factory uses the cutting edge technologies to make über precise
components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A precision mold starts with precision materials. The materials they make use
of here are void free, meaning that there are no microscopic pockets or bubbles
in the material which would make it hard to machine precisely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/megdqy2lxlnd3fm/voidfree.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Pretty sure this specific piece is tungsten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blanks are then given a rough CNC cut, and then brought to a precision
grinder where a worker uses a device to trim all edges. The device scales all
of the workers movements by a large factor, and greatly magnifies the part. A
bouncing rotary tool allows the worker to grind away slowly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/4x2b05ds2o0eux2/cut.gif?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is an ablation process which uses a super high current arc to
blast off material bit by bit and polish the mold and give it a mirror finish
(if I recall correctly).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/oyag7ev874vohmm/ablate.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The polished mold pieces are very pretty!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/e2sq59sqpj393j7/moldpieces.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The finished pieces are then assembled into a mold housing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/3hu5hvlzusjqsal/moldassemble.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The parts are made by injection molding a metal powder into the mold. These are
very delicately held together, you could easily snap them with your bare hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are then forged at high heat, which bonds the metal, making it very strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/84glx83udxsefoo/part.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Hmm… where have I seen this part in the wild ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, this is a process you could hope-to-afford one day when either prices
come down, your company is doing really well, or you are operating in a niche
that requires it. Despite being somewhat inaccessible, it was really cool to
get to see how it all comes together!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mannequin Factory Tour</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/26/sz-adventure-20.1/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/26/sz-adventure-20.1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A question you dread your child asking – where do mannequins come from?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well in today’s blog, we’ll find out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This factory was very perspective changing. Usually, people think of China as
being for knock-off or unoriginal products, but the Mannequin Factory was
somewhat akin to a pop-art-at-scale Andy Warhol-esque plant. There were a lot of
original ideas and very skilled hand craftsmen. The company owner/head artist
was a very charismatic Chinese man, he gave us a really wonderful tour of his
facility!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out some of the really cool pieces designed here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/2pazk2z8pmg4pyb/copper.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/5wng153zi8425g4/zebra.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/rjs58cwipnu0338/punk.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/p3cvvngoizpg86p/trio.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A mannequin starts with a sculptor making a small mockup to play with style and
form:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/vgc343jv7xnagk9/miniman.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the sculptor produces a master mannequin:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/qnnv9ky97uqlp4m/wireframe.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Wireframe model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/k9w1muvcdwi95gg/form.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Shaping the form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From that mannequin, molds are made:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/36t4joza2kkmfls/mold.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the molds, mannequins are cast:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/n43vt195oz4q4ng/glass.gif?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Casts are done using fiberglass&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/t6vj8b42fylz415/sadmold.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
A particularly sad looking mold curing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The factory operates at a pretty large scale!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/bwb58fzt7d7lzwa/scale.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
A lot of casts being made!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like this show because you can see casts being freshly opened and queued for
the next phase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/ppnuf53hatcjucx/opening.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After casting, the mannequins are powdercoated/painted/glossed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/gqmncv9mad2fkcl/painting.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After painting, blemishes are marked and repaired:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/2x84xoewd6mvlcn/blem.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Red tape is used to mark the faults.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Optionally, cosmetics (or other finishing touches) are applied:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/y14zu3padyyb6cl/cosmetics1.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Archives:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They keep copies of various parts of mannequins that they have produced in the
past, in case they want to reference old work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/ov303y4jd3xx0py/archive.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/qp3g7kgxhgyabbk/headarchive.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Headroom?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;water-treatment&quot;&gt;Water Treatment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This factory also has an on-site water treatment facility&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was not quite as involved as the one at the leather treatment facility, but
this factory does do a lot of sanding and painting so they treat their waste
water on-site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/h1aal3z0pfqipgl/water.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;oddities&quot;&gt;Oddities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are definitely odd things to see in a mannequin factory, or if not odd,
visually striking sights. Here are a few images, left without comment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/egatm1nrt2uuo1i/oddity1.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/ivp0qffooeud4e4/oddity2.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/94bornea5wnkxbl/oddity3.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/abkgj1jp4g4ecnb/oddity4.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lastly&quot;&gt;Lastly&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got a really fantastic parting gift at this factory… an arm!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/gxx9rs7oajwwx4k/gift.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be fun to take through customs…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to do a project with it like turn it into a handy desk lamp. It’s made
of a very nice quality wood.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Zipper Factory Tour</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/25/sz-adventure-19/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/25/sz-adventure-19</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Zipper factory tour was courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;http://danielliang.com/randomness/&quot;&gt;Daniel Liang&lt;/a&gt;.
This was one of the more detailed tours; there’s a whole lot that goes into a zipper! Daniel’s factory
is also super large as it is essentially end-to-end, raw materials go in such as bulk plastic and metal, and 
finished spools of zipper material and zips come out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;filament-making&quot;&gt;Filament Making&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Filaments are used to make the plastic zipping ribs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They start out as raw plastic pelts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/n8br4vzqq44xze7/raw_pelts.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a black color is desired, a small amount of dye pellets are added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/7l965n0n6di2wt4/dyed_pelts.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pellets go into the hopper (far left) to be melted down/mixed and then extruded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/jp0i21hx2k4ehkh/filament_pano.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I didn’t get great pictures of this part, but the filaments are
pulled through, cooled, and then spooled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe this picture will help you, but I can’t really make sense of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/749pvs877ijxpfc/extruded.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tape-weaving&quot;&gt;Tape Weaving&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tapes are woven from some nylon/cotton thread. I’m not sure if this is made on
site or not, but I think if I recall it is a separate factory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thread goes into weaving machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/ewpefmt4c3hfgoi/weaver3.gif?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Weaving machine, slowed down many times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/xqmq8galwcy6w2o/weaverarray.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Many arrays of weaving machines. Each machine weaves several tapes at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;zip-integrating&quot;&gt;Zip Integrating&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These machines knit in the filaments into a plastic zipper. This is either onto a woven tape, or standalone (both are pictured below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/tf9ije2g7k0wku9/knit-tape.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/sde4tpradlqmrmz/standalone.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;slider-making&quot;&gt;Slider Making&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Zipper Slider starts out
looking like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/30yzyuzpifdwl8e/IMG_0404.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Raw metal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The metal is melted down and sent to die casting molds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/lqd42depoi45sb4/IMG_0408.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Die casting machines cranking out zips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/03ie51qj76bhl2e/diecast.gif?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Live die casting, metal refil pouring in the background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/7dc639ray9w58j0/diecastscale.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
They make a lot of sliders!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/jnowflshwct6sqc/IMG_0403.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Die cast pieces coming out of the mold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the pieces go through multiple polishing phases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/heoqlh1027reqgn/IMG_0418.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Separated pieces going into the polisher. One of ~5 polish phases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, some assembly of the flap and the zip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/vp2jjp6y839a0w6/zip_assemble.gif?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Putting together the zipper metal components by hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/7n41t42b6q8mcfv/auto_assemble.gif?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Less specialized zipper assemblies are automated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/cv1pqe54yijs3fl/auto_assemble2.gif?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
The alignment process involves a properly shaped “needle” and a vibrating, spinning bowl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;packaging&quot;&gt;Packaging&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/t64pz1vw0gthzk5/spindle2.gif?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Chord spindling machine. Back and forth makes it tidy for sale!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/194k2isakds9mq9/spindle.gif?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Chord spindling machine release.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Leather Factory Tour</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/23/sz-adventure-17/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/23/sz-adventure-17</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today we visited the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.primeasialeather.com&quot;&gt;PrimeAsia Leather&lt;/a&gt; Factory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/p6m1pr5llmmihbb/IMG_0298.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;Welcome to PrimeAsia&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
A warm welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/3hz414mnjf3inrt/IMG_0300.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
A ‘real’ welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The leather comes in to the factory pre-treated. The tannery is (typically) these days co-located with the slaughterhouse.
At the tannery they chrome treat the raw leather and then put it in a shipping container to wherever it is going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/5gy8408la8tarxb/IMG_0305.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Pile of raw leather “wet blues”, waiting to be processed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/3exymrt58a479wr/IMG_0303.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Quality Inspection&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The leather is then cut through the middle (ie, reducing the thickness) to a top-grain piece and a suede piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/otbddrkajga1cvg/splice.gif?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The suede leather is then buffed down to standardize thickness. (the top-grain needs no buffing as it is cut to the right size).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The leather dust is then captured and put into random products, like asphalt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/eag7mdd45ckwwtf/IMG_0317.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Leather dust&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The leathers are then dyed in these big tumblers. They can do any color – they mix chemicals on site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/i2f1j96qrmicvzt/dye.gif?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh that tumbler was just a baby, for color testing and sample runs. No. This is a tumbler:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/pdq54x61p517n0v/big_dye.gif?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Look at the people to get a sense of scale&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/xhxmcjob73ktvm7/IMG_0346.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
The dyed leather comes off the line&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;post-processing&quot;&gt;Post Processing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a myriad of leather post processing steps depending on the finished product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can turn a cow into a crocodile:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/kxvpjvd839l795m/IMG_0368.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is done by melting a plastic sheet into the leather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can embed thermal-color change wax:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/qiw5brassdcsuvv/thermal_wax.gif?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bright pink dyed and super soft suede:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/ps2nuscf4uy7sia/IMG_0361.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waterproofed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/lhd1pwenz7ymnoh/IMG_0366.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;testing&quot;&gt;Testing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A really cool section was the testing facilities. This ensures the quality of the finished product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/m0gp4niqisne6eo/testing.gif?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are machines that can test the rigidity, flexibility, waterproofness, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;water-purification&quot;&gt;Water Purification&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leather is notorious for pollution. At PrimeAsia, they have a big and fancy water purification plant on-site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/zxla0m2xis6xnhg/IMG_0382.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
We start our tour from the control panel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/u6bfabjt9m9dqk4/IMG_0384.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Water starts out a bit frothy (I believe it’s a bacterial processing phase)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/cj1sf134gs634nh/IMG_0387.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Water is cleaner!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/6be038hipisdfzf/IMG_0389.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Clean water comes out here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;trivia&quot;&gt;Trivia&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leather is cheaper than I thought. It was maybe $100 for a whole pelt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no natural leather color. After chrome tanning, all leather is blue-gray.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Shenzhen Maker Faire</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/20/sz-adventure-14/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/20/sz-adventure-14</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We were lucky enough to overlap our stay with the Shenzhen Maker Faire!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/v00lmytnibmbqzf/IMG_0270.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;Panorama of  the faire&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/dpl8xi72jf3i8pg/IMG_0268.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;Panorama of  the faire&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a lot of drones…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/p4acqzacf4bpp1z/IMG_0252.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;Drones! Drones everywhere&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I even ran into some friends!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/ihnsvo6iu1ufcsx/IMG_0262.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mentisoasis&quot;&gt;Lizhou Sha&lt;/a&gt; MIT ‘18&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/n0urvuvezbx8odi/1972495_1615199928734038_5094817963364884169_n.jpg?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/debweinswig&quot;&gt;Deb Weinswig&lt;/a&gt;, my cousin!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finished off the day at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://hackaday.com/2015/06/29/the-spirit-of-hackaday-shines-in-shenzhen/&quot;&gt;Hackaday pizza party&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What struck me most is that we were like an hour out of the city by subway but it still looked like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/5wxvgeb5j8pmdie/IMG_0267.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;Skyscrapers&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amount of construction in the region is insane.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How is Shenzhen so green?</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/19/sz-adventure-13/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/19/sz-adventure-13</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Watering trucks! Saw this during a night out. They go around and spray
down all the fancy greenery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/qmza1bv8utlid9z/IMG_0244.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/ecvqb87fe50re94/IMG_0243.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Engineering Query at King Kredie</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/18/sz-adventure-12/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/18/sz-adventure-12</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/90unrey3pm2fmft/engquer.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Inside the King Kredie Engineering Query room&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Day 9 I mentioned that we had submitted our boards for Engineering Queries,
but I didn’t quite explain what those are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re working with a good manufacturer, they don’t just blindly produce
what you tell them, they will go through and verify certain properties of the
design to make sure it will come out as expected, or even tell you ways you can
save costs that you may not have thought of. This is because:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;they want your future business&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;they’re just good people&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;they don’t make more money on the more expensive process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 can happen because a different process may have no different labor cost, but
just a material cost which they don’t mark up. This is an important point to
keep in mind when working with various manufacturers – they will pass savings
on to you if possible!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Flex PCB Factory Tour at King Kredie</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/18/sz-adventure-12.1/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/18/sz-adventure-12.1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While we were doing the Engineering Query at King Kredie, we also got a
special bonus tour: Flex PCB Manufacturing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flex PCB is kind of the future – as devices get smaller, a thick-old-green PCB is
no longer practical unless it is also a structural element. Flex PCB’s, traditionally used 
more often as a custom connector, can be populated with components as well so are a really cool
technique to experiment with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process is pretty different from traditional PCB etching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You start with a big roll of copper foil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/bblzqgz89ygqe25/foil.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Punch out a pattern using a big press.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/vm0nhnl0zgvgifu/cut.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The die looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/mair9oscbir97ch/die.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you laminate it. The laminate sheet has also been punch cut appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/huupl28achi91lm/laminate.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
An iron is used to bond the plastic laminate to the copper/backing laminate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you (optionally) silkscreen print on&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/s7dzg4g17f1qba1/silk.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Alignment is not critical here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finished product:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/b8jp50qy9ksxxxf/finished.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
This flexpcb has a stiff copper trace inside of it as well for rigidity on that axis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on, these will need to be cut out/depanelized.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Tea Ceremony</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/17/sz-adventure-11.3/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/17/sz-adventure-11.3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/uku47k5rpa0yndd/tea.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The printing press guys were really the best – so good, they get three posts
for one day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following our visit, they taught us how to do – and appreciate – the
traditional tea ceremony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make the tea ceremony, first you use hot water in
a little basin to wash out all of the tea cups. Then, you fill the teapot with
tealeaves, and use the basin (with fresh water) to pour hot water over the
leaves. You stir by gently shaking the tea for 30 seconds, and then pour out
the water. The first wash is thrown out traditionally to make sure the leaves
are clean. Then, you repeat and let steep for a few minutes. You drink all the
tea, and then repeat over multiple washes of the tea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tea they were using was incredibly good; probably the best I’ve ever had.
When we asked where it came from, they told us their friend grew it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-parting-gift&quot;&gt;A parting gift&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The week we were set to leave Shenzhen, the guys from the printing press sent
us a big box of the tea we made the ceremony with. I’ve shared my stash of the
tea with friends and family, sharing my stories from Shenzhen, especially the
generosity of everyone who made us so welcome there!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Seaside Lunch and Opium War Museum</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/17/sz-adventure-11.2/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/17/sz-adventure-11.2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;With the guys from the printing press we got lunch in the middle of our tour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went to this lovely restuarant by the sea that had really fantastic seafood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/ux6lrbs6dpazdv7/restaurant.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
The sea is that color from sediment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch, we went to Shenzhen’s Opium war musuem and saw some of the
exhibits.  It was really interesting to see the Chinese perspective on this
era, and the museum itself was interesting architecturally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/re9whccma38aa2f/thegang.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
The MIT Crew entering the museum&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/xl51f6s0lnrda3f/warroom.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/g8mm2umt8a67e3p/tig.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/eaerawd3m4tzhbc/zombies.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Printing Press Tour</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/17/sz-adventure-11.1/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/17/sz-adventure-11.1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today we got to see a printing press. Printing presses are pretty cool; they’re a pretty old technology which one might
argue was the driving force behind the renaissance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;printing&quot;&gt;Printing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Printing presses are fast. If you’re looking to get something made at one of these factories, you need to order at least something
like 10,000 copies because it prints that many in about the time they can turn the machine on and off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gold-leafing&quot;&gt;Gold Leafing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the coolest processes we got to see at the factory was how they gold-leaf page edges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, they sand down the edges of a block of paper to be super smooth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then they press a piece of foil onto it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result is very shiny!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;paper-cutter&quot;&gt;Paper Cutter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine cutting a piece of paper. Now two pieces. Four? 16? 32? At a certain point, the paper becomes too thick to easily cut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now imagine you aren’t just trying to cut it, but you’re try to make a perfect edge, uniformly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a printing press, they cut thousands of sheets simultaneously. That requires a really sharp knife, a lot of pressure, and a highly attentive worker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the factory, pages are typically cut twice. The first time is to cut to the general size of the job and the second time is done as a trim on the finished product to remove the edges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;binding&quot;&gt;Binding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These big rotary machines are used to bind pages&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-requests&quot;&gt;Special Requests&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Printing presses – or at least this very awesome one – can accommodate a lot of special requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few examples of special processes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Adding a bookmark&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Plastic window&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Bootcamp Project Update</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/15/sz-adventure-9/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/15/sz-adventure-9</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today we wrapped up our electrical changes to the orchard board. At the end of
the day, we submitted our boards for Engineering Queries and price quotes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also added some sweet graphics to my board, this is what is will look like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://shenzhenadventure.files.wordpress.com/2015/06/boardtop.png?w=271&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://shenzhenadventure.files.wordpress.com/2015/06/boardbottom.png?w=261&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing people often ask is how bad the pollution is… Actually Shenzhen is
basically a physically greener city than any other I’ve been to and the air is
very clear. Of course, some days are better than others, today was particularly
clear. What does suck is that everyone is smoking everywhere; that is probably
worse for the air quality than other factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://shenzhenadventure.files.wordpress.com/2015/06/img_0080.jpg?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus office selfie from Hax:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://shenzhenadventure.files.wordpress.com/2015/06/img_0079.jpg?w=225&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After work, we went out to dinner at Coco Park, the notorious clubbing part of
Shenzhen. We didn’t go clubbing, but we went to a pretty western-menued bar
&amp;amp; grill for beers and dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Security via Glitter</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/15/sz-adventure-9.1/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/15/sz-adventure-9.1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So you find yourself in China, and you want to go out in the evening. How can you be sure that your electronics aren’t tampered with?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use tamper evident seals!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/uo0cpvfybqm8j7m/glitter_sealed.jpeg?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically you go and buy a big plastic bin, tape over the edges,
paint glitter nailpolish over the tape, and take a picture. You can’t get into the box without destroying the seals/re-aligning them perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Reasonably Secure”&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Hard Earned Day Off</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/14/sz-adventure-8/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/14/sz-adventure-8</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today was basically a day off, I answered emails and worked on a small project,
as well as doing a couple edits to my board design to get feedback from Bunnie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening, we went to get dinner at a Pakistani restaurant. After dinner,
Akiba led us on his ritual treat; Mango slushies and foot massages. I didn’t
get many photos of the massage, but it was pretty awesome. For about 10 USD,
you get an hour massage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you take a long tea-foot bath. After brewing for a few minutes, you plop
your feet out and the massage begins. They start by filing down your feet and
chiseling them to get rid of dead skin and callouses. Then you get some
standard massage-y stuff. Then, it gets interesting. The masseuse pulls out a
small torch and lights it on fire. Then, she quickly flips a glass cup over the
flame (which is held dangerously close…) and slips it on your foot and
suckers it off. This is the famed practice of cupping. After doing lots of
quick cups, some larger ones are placed on and left to sit for a few minutes.
These ones really hurt! Actually, come to think of it most of the massage
hurt… Anyways, after cupping the remainder of the massage was fairly normal.
My feet felt pretty fucking awesome afterwards, not bad for 65 RMB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://shenzhenadventure.files.wordpress.com/2015/06/img_0077.jpg?w=225&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Intro to Bootcamp Project</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/13/sz-adventure-6/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/13/sz-adventure-6</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Friday and Saturday were free form days, we just worked on our projects for the most part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our projects are basically to doing a small customization to the Orchard platform, which the instructors designed. In a nutshell:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Orchard is a low-power, multi-band radio-connected embedded computing solution. In other words, it's an IoT platform.

Orchard is open source hardware and software.

Orchard is also a supply chain solution. Derivatives of Orchard are meant to be prototyped easily and brought to volume manufacturing with less effort than typical. Unlike breadboard solutions like Arduino, Orchard is targeted toward prototyping through board spins. This is possible thanks to China's low-cost prototyping infrastructure. The effort to prototype is higher than a breadboard, but the on-ramp to scale production once you've got your design finished is also less steep.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Orchard is really cool, you can read more about it &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kosagi.com/w/index.php?title=Orchard_Main_Page&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My customization is adding a sensor chip called an APDS 9960. It’s a hell of a sensor: it can do ambient light, proximity, and gesture sensing baked into a tiny tiny package and communicates over I2C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://shenzhenadventure.files.wordpress.com/2015/06/apds9960.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally I was going to try to do a radio astronomy antenna on the board, so that you could chuck out a bunch of orchard boards in a field and make a radio telescope, but getting the RF engineering correct was going to be too difficult for the scope of the course and my background in said materials.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Learning the Ropes</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/11/sz-adventure-5/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/11/sz-adventure-5</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today we were again mostly in-house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We kicked off the day with a lecture on how to use Altium (pcb design software)
by Bunnie.  Afterwards, we got lunch at this super awesome Thai restaurant
right by our office (they have very filling lunch specials for 45 RMB / 7.25
USD). I was going to go to another restaurant, but it started to pour (seems to
rain most days so far around noon).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch, it was mostly just working time. Artem and I decided to go to Seg,
the super large electronics market to get keyboards and mice so that we can
easily use Altium. We got super side tracked in segbuy and ended up walking
around for hours, but it was good because we also found inspiration in the
millions of parts available there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One funny thing I learned is that if you’re looking for a single item, and the
manufacturer is selling high quantity, saying you want a sample is a great way
to get one at a low cost, but it feels somewhat dishonest. Then again, Seg
doesn’t feel quite honest either…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After burning far to much time visitng all 10 floors of Seg twice, we headed
back to the office, did some work thinking about our designs, and then headed
to dinner. Saquib and I decided to go to the restaurant we were going to go to
earlier – it’s a vegetarian restaurant so we were pretty excited to be able to
order anything off the menu! The place was a little bit dingy, but the food was
pretty great and not too expensive – 52 RMB / 8.4 USD comfortably fed us both
– usually vegetarian restaurants are pricey because of low demand. Was pumped
to finally be able to eat the famous ma po tofu! After dinner we went to Gong
Cha, a tea chain. Their teas are awesome, I had a kumquat limeade drink with
pearls and jelly that was super refreshing. Desipite being cheap already, they
had a buy one get one half off thing going so we got 2 large drinks for 22 RMB
/ 3.5 USD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also learned that the word “chisu” I’ve been using for vegetarian sounds a
lot like “chizou” which means stall. That explains why everytime I ask for
vegetarian food they show me the bathroom. Could have been worse! I think the
right word is “su-shi”.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Toy Prototyping Factory Tour</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/10/sz-adventure-4.7/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/10/sz-adventure-4.7</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We visited a toy studio for a to-be-unnamed toy company (hence, no photos).
This place was really cool. Basically, big brands (and not just for toys,
clothes, electronics, etc) spec out a thing they want at a very high level,
such as “make me a toy that looks like a turtle”. They then send it to a
prototyping studio who makes a turtle toy prototype and sends it back for
feedback. So the brands essentially monitor markets and tell the protypers what
to build to meet it.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Assembly Line Factory Tour</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/10/sz-adventure-4.6/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/10/sz-adventure-4.6</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At the AQS plant we also got to see the final assembly of a printer. This was
really awesome. Printers are super complicated builds so they basically have to
be done by hand. Essentially what happens is they have stations with a couple
of tasks on them. A person performs the task, scans a barcode on the item, then
passes the cart to the next person. There were 100-200 stations for this
printer. The barcodes let them make sure each printer has had all steps and
also lets a control center monitor to make sure that they are on point for
meeting the quota for that day and hour. What’s cool is that each station has
an instruction booklet which sets the task. The entire line is essentially a
very long pipeline, so they have to carfully balance the pipeline to prevent
bottlenecks and keep throughput high. It takes multiple revisions to get it
right. Apparently setting up such a line, from end to end, is 3-6 months. Each
printer is also fully tested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/h6z1g7u1eqbzhgh/IMG_0053.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/vi28mwp1lxy8buv/IMG_0055.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Automated Board Population/SMT Factory Tour</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/10/sz-adventure-4.5/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/10/sz-adventure-4.5</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We got to go to AQS to see one of their board population/smt lines. This was fucking awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solder Paste Machine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/uz87gw1hfqhuwjx/IMG_0040.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SMT Machine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/hlv509ncoejegyr/IMG_0043.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Pick and Place&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Inspection&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/rlg40ytvnwzhjyf/IMG_0046.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/09yxcxwh99cnuy9/screen.gif?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Touch up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/2op0w8yqc2ral4j/IMG_0047.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solder machine ( a pool of solder grazes the board)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/9nrt7zu5jbqkvdh/IMG_0049.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>PCB Factory Tour</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/10/sz-adventure-4.4/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/10/sz-adventure-4.4</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;First they hand check the design to conform with their capabilities. They will make minor changes if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/j4il6h2m1w3e6c1/IMG_0038.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next they drill out any holes needed in the boards. They very frequently check the bit quality, and bits are only used for 3000 holes before being swapped out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/j1901rd3d1di9j3/holes.gif?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next they do some electroplating stages&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/0yxdwm3oeekmb14/dip.gif?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here they do the photo chemical processing steps that are light sensitive&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/xs2m11p80pjqywv/IMG_0034.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then they do silkscreening (I’m missing a picture of this…)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/0tvj1gpxcdy4f9o/IMG_0027.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next is depanelization, or cutting out the individual boards from the panel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/3g8enfn3aixzio2/IMG_0025.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finished boards&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/wc6k185fml34nqi/IMG_0028.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next they have Quality Control:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chemical checks that boards have the correct properties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/x6la9qn3a2yndru/IMG_0032.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspecting the boards quality visually, they cut out a chunk of board, encase it in resin and then grind it down to the edge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/cqpi9xtx3wacs9x/IMG_0031.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They also digitally check every single board for continuity/impedance.  This machine essentially has two needles it touches between each point to test,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/jgfp1zp2uqg68we/tester2.gif?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Injection Mold Factory Tour</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/10/sz-adventure-4.3/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/10/sz-adventure-4.3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At this place we got to see them designing and making the molds. This was
pretty crazy to me! Basically you can 3D-model your part and then ship it to
them and they design a mold around it which has all the mechanical parts needed
to make the mold. Once the design is there, they will CNC mill it out roughly.
For finer details, they will do what’s called Electric Deposition, where they
use a finely CNC’ed copper electrode in the mirror image of the design and
repeatedly tap it onto the mold with a massive current running. This eventually
cuts out the design layer by layer by blasting away the steel and copper.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Injection Molding Factory Tour</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/10/sz-adventure-4.2/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/10/sz-adventure-4.2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This was fun! At the injection molder they had a massive pile of not being run molds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/hj1nb7x8d7s7ugo/IMG_0015.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and about 20 machines which were cranking out parts. We got to see our mold for the class pried apart which was cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/llkyy6q9898izvm/IMG_0017.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Molds are super complicated; I didn’t have an appreciation for how hard they are to make before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a run down:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tolerances are ridiculous. They need to be airtight metal with no gaskets so that the plastics don’t leak&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For nice looking parts, the molds need to be basically mirror finish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/ciab2zcmuppm1vx/IMG_0018.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Molds can be made from Aluminium for lower cost but they basically don’t do it in China because Steel is cheap enough there.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A mold will run about $5000-$10000 USD for a reasonably sized design, and can do about 500,000 casts. This is mostly the price of the steel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can modify your mold by welding on a block of steel and then re-carving out the features&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Designs with overhangs or other features are much more complicated to build because the mod needs to essentially unfold itself to be able to release a part&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A mold has a couple key properties, the points where the pins push the cast out and the fill points. Based on these, the finished product will have different flows of plastic through it which could cause different knit points (where two flows meet) or flow lines (artifacts of the plastic’s path). The points where the pins push out are those raised disks you sometimes see on plastic objects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Day 4 Overview</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/10/sz-adventure-4.1/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/10/sz-adventure-4.1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today (Day 4) was awesome, we toured various manufacturers to see the “end to
end” development of a device. I’ve broken out the blogposts on each factory separately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2015/06/10/sz-adventure-4.2/&quot;&gt;Injection Molding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2015/06/10/sz-adventure-4.3/&quot;&gt;Injection Mold Factory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2015/06/10/sz-adventure-4.4/&quot;&gt;PCB Factory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2015/06/10/sz-adventure-4.5/&quot;&gt;Automated SMT/Board Population&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2015/06/10/sz-adventure-4.6/&quot;&gt;Assembly Line&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2015/06/10/sz-adventure-4.7/&quot;&gt;Toy Prototyping Shop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lunch:&lt;/strong&gt;
We went out to lunch with some of the guys from one of the factories to a local
place. The food was great, but a little unfilling as all I had was plain
veggies. Luckily, I decided to keep a jar of peanut butter with me at all times
so I had a couple spoonfuls in the car for protein. I was most intrigued by
eating Gingko in a dish. It’s a kind of “creamy peanut” texture, with a
potato-y taste. There were also these guys sitting near us who had the most
incredible raspy voices, they were speaking an unknown local dialect and were
basically shitfaced at noon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dinner:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jon Lee rejoined us for dinner which was awesome! Of course it meant getting
somewhat inebriated again (this time, baijiu and budweiser bombs). Again, they
made sure there were plenty of options for me to eat which was great! The
restaurant also had these amazing pots of tea, I drank a large volume of that.
I was particularly excited to eat a whole water chesnut (never seen them not
sliced).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Small Bootcamp Update</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/09/sz-adventure-3/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/09/sz-adventure-3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today was mostly an “in house day”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a lecture from Bunnie on the course and then we worked on getting our dev environments set up.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Shenzhen Electronics Market Tour</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/08/sz-adventure-2/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/08/sz-adventure-2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I woke up around 7:30AM, although I didn’t have to be up till 9am. Checking
WeChat, I saw that another student was up and wanted to grab breakfast at 8am.
I responded, then got ready, and then headed out. However, I couldn’t find the
other person so I walked around a bit. I was, at this point, phone-less so I
had to run back up to my room to check messages and communicate. After finding
the other person, we went to a bakery cafe around the corner. I had a really
great “french toast bread”. Talking to the other student, it seemed that my
internet woes were not shared; indeed, trying her connection yielded great
bandwidth, even over vpn. Grumble grumble, I hope I can get mine fixed up a
bit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 10am we all met up and went to a Japanese super market and got some basic
supplies (bananas, instant oatmeal, and soap for me). This place has a lot of
Western goods which is very nice, but was a little bit pricey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then dropped off our bags back at the apartments and headed back out. We
stopped for lunch at a nice restaurant in the mall. I knew eating was going to
be really really hard for me, I was pretty worried. If you don’t know about my
eating restrictions, they’re relatively simple and I’m basically not picky at
all. I used to be vegetarian for a number of years, but I relaxed it for health
reasons. Now I try to avoid “sentient” animals. This basically entails to not
eating any mammals whatsoever and avoiding other intelligent animals such as
octopi or crows. I’m basically fine with any chicken or scaly/bony fish dish.
The other constraint is that I keep somewhat Kosher, so I try to avoid
shellfish. I made peace with the fact that I would likely have slip ups over
the trip. After one meal, let me say this: It’s looking tough. In China, pork
isn’t a meat. It’s a seasoning. Almost everything has pork (and a lot of things
are probably cooked in it regardless). Although there were a lot of things I
couldn’t eat, I ended up being able to have a really awesome ma-style (more on
that in a second) fish stew and spicy potatoes. Ma is a special type of
peppercorn which is really spicy, but also numbs your mouth so you can’t feel
it. It’s almost impossible to get in the States and it is awesome. I’ll have to
look into importing some back for personal use. The other really great thing is
Tea, the whole meal was cup after cup of delicious barley (I think?) tea. I
drank like a gallon of it (although I sweated that out later – Shenzhen is
HOT). When the waitress is pouring you tea, you are supposed to knock on the
table to say thanks. After the meal, the restaurant is supposed to give you tax
voucher slips. I still don’t get this all the way; probably because it makes no
sense. Basically, restaurants pre-pay their tax by purchasing these tax-bills
that they give to customers. Because they can get reimbursed for over
purchasing the tax forms, they would rather not give you them (to under-report
taxes). So instead they will offer you a drink at the restaurant in lieu of tax
form. To combat this, the government added a scratch off lottery ticket onto
the tax slips to incentivize people getting them. To me it seems like a double
down on a broken system, but who am I to judge? Definitely makes taxes more fun
than the states!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch, we went to hackerspace we’ll be calling home briefly to check it
out. The person we needed to talk to was on lunch break, so we went off to do
other things.  I don’t think words can do the next part justice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The electronics markets in Shenzhen are insane. There a skyscrapers on which
each floor is filled with vendors hawking components. The scale is enormous,
and the prices are dirt cheap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/y0jymdoq4mrgyfa/IMG_0010.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
One floor…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/6zeg8yehru2yxaz/IMG_0011.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Two floor, red floor, blue floor…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reels of 10,000 components can be had for less than it would cost to buy 5 of
them at Radio Shack. There are also these incredible “recycling” markets which
take old devices and tear them down and sell the parts. Walking around you can
see people sorting parts from devices. When you go to the next floor, they will
sell a slightly more put back together version and so on and so forth until you
can get ‘new’ devices. It’s hard to explain the bizzareness of these markets.
You can find phones, for example, in the shape of soccer balls, cars, miniature
iphones, phones with a reading light, phones with massive batteries to charge
other phones, and everything else under the sun. I just don’t get who makes the
market for these devices given that you never see them, and even the locals
seem to not have seen them either. For instance, I picked up (along with
several of the other students) the miniature iPhone which runs full android,
has 3g, and works quite well except for the fact that it is tiny as hell but
locals were just as amused as we all were at them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/ke4j5zen5dafzdb/IMG_0014.JPG?raw=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Tiny phone, but runs full android and has 3g!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the tour of the markets, we went back to the hackerspace, did our
errand (getting access cards), and then headed over to dinner with everyone
involved in the course. We went to a fancy Chinese Restaurant (that’s what it
was called) and had an all out feast with all the people supporting the course,
including John Lee (the owner of AQS, a big manufacturing company). This went a
lot better for me than lunch, although I couldn’t eat most things, two of the
guests were very kind in helping me order some tasty foods – having to explain
my dietary preferences is always a challenge, but they were very gracious. I
also had to explain some of my other prefernces, but you’ll have to ask me in
person for that story!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an interesting drinking culture. I’m not sure I fully understand it
yet, but I drank a lot of beer and baijiu (a really great shot alchohol that
varies from either a sour candy/apple juice taste to pretty close to whisky).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, I started to get pretty tired (as were the other students) so we
headed home. I took a quick shower and then passed out for 2 or three hours and
woke up to write this blog post. I also learned some chinese expressions that
might come in handy tomorrow…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Wo chisu. Wo ju-ro nieu-ro be-lay guo-mean.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a vegetarian. I am allergic to pork, beef, and shellfish.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Arriving in Shenzhen</title>
   <link href="/shenzhen/2015/06/07/sz-adventure-1/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/shenzhen/2015/06/07/sz-adventure-1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The flight to Hong Kong was not bad at all! I think I slept most of the way. On
the flight I watched Chappie – definitely go see it if you’re a Die Antword
fan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon arrival, I met up with Sean Cross and another student from the program. We
took a taxi &amp;amp; the metro over to Shenzhen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We quickly checked into our rooms and then, after getting frustrated with the
internet, I went to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>What the #?!* is Bitcoin?</title>
   <link href="/talks/2014/12/24/tedx-beacon-street-2014/"/>
   <updated>2014-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/talks/2014/12/24/tedx-beacon-street-2014</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My TEDx talk is online!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Vzjtvt77mgc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Directional Scope for Filtering Visual Data</title>
   <link href="/musings/2013/08/18/webcam-scope/"/>
   <updated>2013-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>/musings/2013/08/18/webcam-scope</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A telescope where you can look through and point/zoom in a closed environment.
The device will pull content from sources like webcams/google/shodan to provide
relevent content in that direction and zoom level.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
